<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scheduled Process on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/scheduled-process/</link><description>Recent content in Scheduled Process on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/scheduled-process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the very first box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The box is hosting a webserver for a &amp;ldquo;Secret Spy Agency&amp;rdquo;. They seem to concern themselves with gathering intelligence from other agencies, but the website is mostly a tip-line: users can privately submit tips to SSA using their contact form and PGP key.</description></item><item><title>Bashed</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bashed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bashed/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Bashed features an infosec developer&amp;rsquo;s blog. Seemingly, the blog has just one article. That article shows a pretty huge hint for how to complete the box. Bashed is a fairly easy box, but requires a bit of careful observation after obtaining a foothold. As usual, a basic understanding of linux is an asset.
RECON I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/redpanda/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Red Panda is a hilariously cute website that acts as an index for a bunch of photos of red pandas. The red panda photos each have an author marked on them.
When a user visits the site, they may use the search bar to view the photos. When they do, it increments a view counter for that photo. Part of the site describes that the author who contributed the photo is then credited on a per-view basis.</description></item></channel></rss>