<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker Escape on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/docker-escape/</link><description>Recent content in Docker Escape on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/docker-escape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Runner</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/runner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/runner/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Are you ready for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, Anomalies? I sure am! Runner is the very first box of the season. Thankfully, it&amp;rsquo;s a reasonably straightforward Linux box - rated &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; but actually more on the easy side. The box centers around a cloud-based business that offers a CI/CD solution - basically just hosting JetBrains&amp;rsquo; TeamCity and selling it as a service. While many boxes are pretty far-removed from reality, this one was actually made from a very realistic architecture, where customers run containerized CI/CD pipelines and the service provider has some kind of management product to administer and monitor it all.</description></item><item><title>Analytics</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/analytics/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Analytics is still active. The box centers around a fictional analytics company that provides data analysis services using the infrastructure they&amp;rsquo;re hosting. The company is running a popular open-source analytics / BI platform. This box uses a modern architecture, reflective of how real websites run these days (when they&amp;rsquo;re on-prem).
For each step of Analytics, the skill emphasis is placed firmly on enumeration.</description></item><item><title>Cybermonday</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Cybermondaywas just released! It is the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The site is a fictional e-commerce site. This box will test your knowledge of SQL, broken authentication, and definitely all the JWT tricks you can imagine! Have fun.
RECON nmap scans For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous boxes in the Open Beta Season II.</description></item></channel></rss>