<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>XSS on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/xss/</link><description>Recent content in XSS on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/xss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cat</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cat was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice&amp;hellip; and it was an absolute delight! If you&amp;rsquo;re searching for a fun box to try some web attacks, look no further!
Plus, what is more fitting for a web-oriented box than a website for ranking cute cat photos? &amp;#x1f431;
Recon was easy, as long as .git is in your go-to dirbusting wordlist. Once discovering the exposed .git directory, you can read through the target&amp;rsquo;s website source code.</description></item><item><title>Alert</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/alert/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/alert/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Alert was released between seasons 6 and 7. I came to Alert after a substantial hiatus, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did! It was pretty fun. Even though it is marked as Easy, I found the foothold challenging. Privesc to root was also very pleasant, albeit quick.
Recon is pretty simple on this one. Most of what we need can be obtained through a scan for subdomains and a crawl of the main website.</description></item><item><title>Sea</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sea/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Sea was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, Heist. With proper recon, it&amp;rsquo;s a very short box. Perhaps they will fix it after the season ends, but this box actually comes pre-exploited: to gain foothold, all you have to do is find the exploit and use it. It&amp;rsquo;s totally doable to figure out how to exploit it yourself though - that&amp;rsquo;s the method that I&amp;rsquo;ll outline in this walkthrough.</description></item><item><title>Intuition</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I hope that Runner got you warmed up for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, Anomalies&amp;hellip; because you&amp;rsquo;re going to need it - this one is tough! Intuition was released as the second box of the season, requiring a wide array of skills to complete. Intuition is very long: by my count, it has ten distinct steps to overcome (which classifies it as being on the harder end of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; difficulty). Interestingly though, Intuition requires very little in terms of &amp;ldquo;exploitation&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about finding and abusing simple misconfigurations/mistakes - which, I think, makes it a more realistic scenario than many HTB boxes.</description></item><item><title>Headless</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/headless/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/headless/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION The penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV Savage Lands, released for week 12, is Headless. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been participating in the season, this is one of the few boxes that I attempted within the 1 week limit. It was totally worth it! This box is an absolute delight, and I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it enough. There aren&amp;rsquo;t any rabbit-holes on this one, and most of the effort will simply be to gain a foothold.</description></item><item><title>Phonebook</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/phonebook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/phonebook/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Phonebook is currently active (Oct 2021) and worth 30 points.
FIRST TAKE I started up the challenge and visited the website. It is a small login form.
Looks pretty typical. Checking the source code for another look reveals a conspicuous little script:
&amp;lt;script&amp;gt; const queryString = window.location.search; if (queryString) { const urlParams = new URLSearchParams(queryString); const message = urlParams.get(&amp;#39;message&amp;#39;); if (message) { document.</description></item></channel></rss>