<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SMB on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/smb/</link><description>Recent content in SMB on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/smb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SolarLab</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION SolarLab was released as the fourth box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. Although it&amp;rsquo;s rated Medium, I would rate it more like an Easy. The box is about a company of three employees that are creating an instant messaging platform. The background is largely unimportant for the solution, though.
This box takes little to no recon. Checking the SMB share will give you want you need to get started. Reading through or spidering the initial website on port 80 will lead you towards a subdomain on another port, where you will find a nice little web challenge for exploiting inadequate input validation / sanitization and a vulnerable backend PDF-generation library.</description></item><item><title>Windows PrivEsc</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/windows-privesc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/windows-privesc/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION While doing the HTB box Love for my my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series, I encountered a privilege escalation technique that I had never seen. Thankfully, the technique was very clearly outlined within this TryHackMe room. Since the room contained such a useful tip, why not go complete the whole thing?
TASK 1 Deploy the VM Connect to the VPN and click the Start Machine button to start up the VM.</description></item><item><title>Blue</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Blue is a retired Windows box, the first box in my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. It ranks as one of the easiest Windows boxes. I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a whole spree of boxes to try to brush up on my Windows technique. In the end, this box was more of an exercise in trying a whole bunch of exploits and dealing with really messed-up python environments.
tldr; If you&amp;rsquo;re doing this box in 2024 or later, go straight to a more recent version of the exploit.</description></item><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is Gofer is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Gofer is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work.</description></item><item><title>Authority</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/authority/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Authority was released as the fifth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Is a &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; Windows box, but will serve as a formidable challenge to any players unfamiliar with Windows. Authority features a typical Microsoft environment, including Microsoft IIS server, LDAP, Kerberos, and SMB. No SSH here! You&amp;rsquo;ll have to rely on more rudimentary remote-connection methods. This box will test your filesystem enumeration skills, but not as much as your PKI knowledge.</description></item></channel></rss>