<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Path Abuse on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/path-abuse/</link><description>Recent content in Path Abuse on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/path-abuse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is Gofer is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Gofer is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work.</description></item><item><title>Busqueda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION For folks like myself that have nada espanol, it turns out &amp;ldquo;busqueda&amp;rdquo; is Spanish for &amp;ldquo;search&amp;rdquo;. It should be no surprise that this box is a search engine. Or rather, it is an aggregator of several search engines all in one.
Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers. No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.
RECON I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item><item><title>Bashed</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bashed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bashed/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Bashed features an infosec developer&amp;rsquo;s blog. Seemingly, the blog has just one article. That article shows a pretty huge hint for how to complete the box. Bashed is a fairly easy box, but requires a bit of careful observation after obtaining a foothold. As usual, a basic understanding of linux is an asset.
RECON I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Precious is an Easy Linux box on HackTheBox, released on November 26, 2022. Its high rating and easy difficulty make it an attactive way to get back into HTB after a short hiatus. It prominently features the Ruby language, and usage of ruby gems - hence the name. While the foothold is fairly straightforward, the path to root takes a bit of thought!
RECON [04:00:40] Performing nmap initial scan:</description></item></channel></rss>