<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WAF on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/waf/</link><description>Recent content in WAF on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/waf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Filter Bypass Techniques</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/filter-bypass/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/filter-bypass/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="why-write-this">Why write this?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Too often, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself in a situation where I needed to bypass some kind of filter and wanted a checklist to reference. However, when searching for such a checklist, I encounter two difficulties with the references I find:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Information is far too task-specific. Many are only about XSS filter evasion, or only about WAFs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There&amp;rsquo;s just too much. Many of these references have hundreds of different techniques to try. And that&amp;rsquo;s great, if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to hack the Pentagon, but for a Easy-to-Medium HTB box it&amp;rsquo;s way overkill.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This post is primarily a reference for myself. Consider it a &amp;ldquo;greatest hits&amp;rdquo; collection of filter bypasses that I have personal experiences with. I won&amp;rsquo;t be explaining how they work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in &lt;em>Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy &lt;em>effects&lt;/em> to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals. The root flag is quick, but requires wrapping your head around some cryptography concepts and formulating a customized solution to overcome the problem.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>