<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bloodhound on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/bloodhound/</link><description>Recent content in Bloodhound on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/bloodhound/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forest</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/forest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/forest/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> is 100% Active Directory&lt;/strong>. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a box with no webserver and only AD is a bit like staring at a blank wall - it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know where to start with enumeration. &lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> is fantastic practice to break you out of that mindset, and help understand good methods for attacking AD environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon mostly consists of going through checklists of ways to enumerate active directory in an unauthenticated manner. It helps a lot to know a few good methods to try, and see how far that gets you. &lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> was all about being methodical and knowing when you&amp;rsquo;ve found something useful. The only thing we really need to realize during recon is that &lt;strong>Kerberos preauthentication is disabled&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my opinion, &lt;em>Freelancer&lt;/em> was a very tough box. It was released as the 7th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s about attacking an Active Directory environment that&amp;rsquo;s running a freelancer job market website. Solving this box requires a wide array of skills. However, while a many skills are required, none of the individual steps in the solution are painfully difficult. It is a long box though, with roughly equal amounts of labour required for foothold, the user flag, and for privilege escalation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>