<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSTI on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/ssti/</link><description>Recent content in SSTI on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/ssti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IClean</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION In my opinion, IClean was a really cool box. It provides a pleasant balance of recon, exploitation, and CTF-style puzzle-solving. This box provides a more realistic web attack surface than many other boxes - there are lots of pages to explore, and many ways that one could think to attack them. I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend IClean to anyone that wants a reasonably challenging (but not too long) web-focused box. Personally, I think this one is on the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; side of medium difficulty.</description></item><item><title>SolarLab</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION SolarLab was released as the fourth box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. Although it&amp;rsquo;s rated Medium, I would rate it more like an Easy. The box is about a company of three employees that are creating an instant messaging platform. The background is largely unimportant for the solution, though.
This box takes little to no recon. Checking the SMB share will give you want you need to get started. Reading through or spidering the initial website on port 80 will lead you towards a subdomain on another port, where you will find a nice little web challenge for exploiting inadequate input validation / sanitization and a vulnerable backend PDF-generation library.</description></item><item><title>Perfection</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/perfection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/perfection/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Perfection was released as the 9th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;, but I&amp;rsquo;m coming to it two weeks late. I really enjoyed this box, even though it was quite easy. I always appreciate when the box creator builds a little bit of a narrative around the box: in this case, we were dealing with a small school and the interaction between two people (shown on the About Us page) regarding the school&amp;rsquo;s computer systems.</description></item><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the very first box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The box is hosting a webserver for a &amp;ldquo;Secret Spy Agency&amp;rdquo;. They seem to concern themselves with gathering intelligence from other agencies, but the website is mostly a tip-line: users can privately submit tips to SSA using their contact form and PGP key.</description></item><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/redpanda/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Red Panda is a hilariously cute website that acts as an index for a bunch of photos of red pandas. The red panda photos each have an author marked on them.
When a user visits the site, they may use the search bar to view the photos. When they do, it increments a view counter for that photo. Part of the site describes that the author who contributed the photo is then credited on a per-view basis.</description></item></channel></rss>