<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LFI on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/lfi/</link><description>Recent content in LFI on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/lfi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lantern</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Is it Linux? I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure&amp;hellip; &amp;#x1f914;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Lantern&lt;/em>, the third box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>, claims to be a Linux box, but in most respects actually it&amp;rsquo;s actually running things as one might in Windows. It isn&amp;rsquo;t until the very end of privesc to root that we find anything Linux-specific. &lt;em>Lantern&lt;/em> is about a generic IT services company running a landing page and an admin panel. What made this one a little special is its extensive use of &lt;em>Blazor&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pov</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pov/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pov/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>HTB released &lt;em>Pov&lt;/em> during Season IV. I didn&amp;rsquo;t play that season, so I&amp;rsquo;m coming to it a few months after. I learned a lot from this box; it really helped me polish my skills for attacking Windows using a Linux box. The pathway to the root flag is very interesting, and requires a wide array of skills. Having just completed my walkthrough for &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/">Mailing&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, this box was refreshingly straightforward: there was no guesswork, and every step led quite logically into the next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mailing</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Mailing&lt;/em> was released as the third box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. The box is initially about a mail server (although that ceases to be important after a foothold is achieved).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To gain a foothold, you need to make some major assumptions using a &amp;ldquo;guess and check&amp;rdquo; procedure that is not easily automated. The foothold is possible by means of exploiting a CVE for an application that you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure is even running on the target. Moreover, the exploit requires user interaction, which you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure is even happening.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Love</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/love/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a week, but now it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back into my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. &lt;em>Love&lt;/em> is the fifth box, following &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/">&lt;em>Toolbox&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. This box was pretty interesting, definitely worth checking out. I really enjoyed that it avoided the whole &amp;ldquo;Find the CVE and exploit it&amp;rdquo; pattern that many Easy boxes use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It revolves around a &amp;ldquo;File Scanner&amp;rdquo; web app with some terrible security misconfigurations and mistakes. Can you find them all?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cybermonday</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, &lt;em>Cybermonday&lt;/em>was just released! It is the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. The site is a fictional e-commerce site. This box will test your knowledge of SQL, broken authentication, and definitely all the JWT tricks you can imagine! Have fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/index%20page.png" alt="title picture">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="nmap-scans">nmap scans&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous boxes in the &lt;em>Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. I set up a directory for the box, with a &lt;code>nmap&lt;/code> subdirectory. Then set &lt;code>$RADDR&lt;/code> to my target machine&amp;rsquo;s IP, and scanned it with a simple but broad port scan:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Download</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Download&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the eighth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em> (Half done the season now!). When &lt;em>Download&lt;/em> was released, it was originally marked as Medium - now it is Hard. I agree with this: discovering vulnerabilities on the box was quite obscure, more like a Hard difficulty box, but once you find those vulnerabilities, exploiting them is relatively easy. Gaining a foothold is the hardest part of &lt;em>Download&lt;/em>, happening in two steps: the first requires careful code analysis and possibly creating some tools of your own; the second requires a creative re-application of techniques usually used for a different type of application. For privilege escalation A bit of knowledge of &lt;em>the old ways&lt;/em> of privilege escalation will be invaluable for getting the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>