<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Common Program Privesc on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/common-program-privesc/</link><description>Recent content in Common Program Privesc on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 12:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/common-program-privesc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sau</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the fourth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. Sau is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; Linux box, named after its creator, &lt;strong>sau123&lt;/strong>. At face value, the box is a server hosting a web-app for collecting and displaying HTTP requests. The user is able to define &amp;ldquo;baskets&amp;rdquo; to catch requests, where the requests and their responses can later be analyzed - including their body and headers. Sau is a well-made easy box, with a straightforward path to the end. The foothold has multiple steps, emphasizing the importance of good enumeration and research. Once foothold is gained, recognition and understanding of the underlying vulnerability will ensure a quick sprint to the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traverxec</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Traverxec is an older box, dating back to 2019, created by a reasonably-famous HTB user named &lt;strong>jkr&lt;/strong>. It prominently features a very minimal webserver called &lt;strong>Nostromo&lt;/strong>. Nostromo is a quick win, reinforcing some key pentesting fundamentals: checking for CVEs and vulnerability recognition while on the local system (after gaining foothold). The procedure for this box is fairly straightforward - a little Linux knowledge will grant the root flag.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I wrote this walkthrough before I had figured out a methodical and consistent way to take notes. Please excuse the haphazard formatting and brevity.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>