<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Common Program Privesc on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/common-program-privesc/</link><description>Recent content in Common Program Privesc on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 12:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/common-program-privesc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sau</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the fourth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Sau is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; Linux box, named after its creator, sau123. At face value, the box is a server hosting a web-app for collecting and displaying HTTP requests. The user is able to define &amp;ldquo;baskets&amp;rdquo; to catch requests, where the requests and their responses can later be analyzed - including their body and headers.</description></item><item><title>Traverxec</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Traverxec is an older box, dating back to 2019, created by a reasonably-famous HTB user named jkr. It prominently features a very minimal webserver called Nostromo. Nostromo is a quick win, reinforcing some key pentesting fundamentals: checking for CVEs and vulnerability recognition while on the local system (after gaining foothold). The procedure for this box is fairly straightforward - a little Linux knowledge will grant the root flag.
I wrote this walkthrough before I had figured out a methodical and consistent way to take notes.</description></item></channel></rss>