<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Java on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/java/</link><description>Recent content in Java on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crafty</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/crafty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/crafty/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Crafty&lt;/em> is an easy-rated Windows box, released for week 6 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV &lt;em>Savage Lands&lt;/em>. This box centers around exploitation of &lt;code>log4j&lt;/code> - maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it &amp;#x1f602; It was a really big deal in 2021. While the disaster that ensued caused heaps of damage, &lt;em>very little actually changed&lt;/em> as a result of its occurrence. If anything can be said for it, at least it stoked the international dialog on supply-chain attacks and &lt;em>the failing health of the open-source ecosystem&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this guide, &lt;em>RegistryTwo&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the sixth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. This box truly lives up to the level of &amp;ldquo;Insane&amp;rdquo;. Every step requires a very good grasp of hacking fundamentals. &lt;em>RegistryTwo&lt;/em> features a mixture of both open-source code and APIs, and homebrew Java applications. Careful code analysis skills and a very strong Java background is essential. This box will require you to either do a bit of coding or extensively modify some existing tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/redpanda/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Red Panda is a hilariously cute website that acts as an index for a bunch of photos of red pandas. The red panda photos each have an author marked on them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a user visits the site, they may use the search bar to view the photos. When they do, it increments a view counter for that photo. Part of the site describes that the author who contributed the photo is then credited on a per-view basis. So not only does the site serve photos, it is also logging and processing the count of views for each photo.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>