<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nmap on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/nmap/</link><description>Recent content in Nmap on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/nmap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WifineticTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION As the 11th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;, WifineticTwo was released mid-March 2024. Although it&amp;rsquo;s officially rated as medium difficulty, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely on the easier side of medium. The skills required to root this box are pretty minimal, but it does require a little out of the box thinking. This box was a lot of fun, in the end. Take the name as a hint &amp;#x1f609;
Upon starting the box, OpenPLC is the first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll notice.</description></item><item><title>Web Enumeration</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/web-enumeration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/web-enumeration/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Why write this? Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve settled into a pretty good set of web enumeration techniques. As I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing more and more walkthroughs, it has started feeling quite repetetive always writing about the same web enumeration strategy. Why not skip that whole song-and-dance, and write it on a separate page that I can link to?
Most importantly, I like having a convenient reference for myself: it really speeds up recon on a box when you have exactly the right enumeration commands at your fingertips.</description></item><item><title>Blue</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Blue is a retired Windows box, the first box in my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. It ranks as one of the easiest Windows boxes. I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a whole spree of boxes to try to brush up on my Windows technique. In the end, this box was more of an exercise in trying a whole bunch of exploits and dealing with really messed-up python environments.
tldr; If you&amp;rsquo;re doing this box in 2024 or later, go straight to a more recent version of the exploit.</description></item></channel></rss>