<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nmap on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/nmap/</link><description>Recent content in Nmap on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/nmap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WifineticTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the 11th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;, &lt;em>WifineticTwo&lt;/em> was released mid-March 2024. Although it&amp;rsquo;s officially rated as medium difficulty, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely on the easier side of medium. The skills required to root this box are pretty minimal, but it does require a little &lt;em>out of the box&lt;/em> thinking. This box was a lot of fun, in the end. Take the name as a hint &amp;#x1f609;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upon starting the box, OpenPLC is the first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll notice. It&amp;rsquo;s archived software, used for turning various devices into software-based PLCs - things like Arduinos and Raspberry Pis, where you can get pin-by-pin access to inputs and outputs. Thankfully though, it also supports x86 Linux architecture, which will lead into an easy initial foothold. Just read about prior exploits for this software and you&amp;rsquo;ll have a shell in no time. First blood for the user flag on this box took less than 8 minutes. Frankly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even follow my usual recon procedure, because the exploit to gain foothold seemed readily apparent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web Enumeration</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/web-enumeration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/web-enumeration/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="why-write-this">Why write this?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve settled into a pretty good set of web enumeration techniques. As I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing more and more &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/">walkthroughs&lt;/a>, it has started feeling quite repetetive always writing about the same web enumeration strategy. Why not skip that whole song-and-dance, and write it on a separate page that I can link to?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most importantly, &lt;em>I like having a convenient reference for myself: it really speeds up recon on a box when you have exactly the right enumeration commands at your fingertips&lt;/em>. This way, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to spend any time formulating the perfect &lt;code>ffuf&lt;/code> command; I can just copy-paste from my previous work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blue</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Blue&lt;/em> is a retired Windows box, the first box in my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. It ranks as one of the easiest Windows boxes. I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a whole spree of boxes to try to brush up on my Windows technique. In the end, this box was more of an exercise in trying a whole bunch of exploits and dealing with really messed-up python environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>tldr;&lt;/strong>
If you&amp;rsquo;re doing this box in 2024 or later, go straight to a more recent version of the exploit. After you finish Recon, &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/#running-eternalblue">just skip right to this part of the walkthrough&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>