<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Broken Authentication on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/broken-authentication/</link><description>Recent content in Broken Authentication on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/broken-authentication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Armaxis</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/armaxis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/armaxis/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Starting the challenge, we&amp;rsquo;re given two ports, corresponding to two components: a website and an web-based email client. The website presents a simple login/registration form, and the email client brings us straight into an inbox without any authentication:
A quick skim through the website code suggests that this email client will probably be used for password resets.
CODE ANALYSIS As usual, I like to read through the code sequentially, starting from startup/initialization code (the Dockerfile, then index.</description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION In my opinion, Freelancer was a very tough box. It was released as the 7th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. It&amp;rsquo;s about attacking an Active Directory environment that&amp;rsquo;s running a freelancer job market website. Solving this box requires a wide array of skills. However, while a many skills are required, none of the individual steps in the solution are painfully difficult. It is a long box though, with roughly equal amounts of labour required for foothold, the user flag, and for privilege escalation.</description></item><item><title>Cybermonday</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Cybermondaywas just released! It is the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The site is a fictional e-commerce site. This box will test your knowledge of SQL, broken authentication, and definitely all the JWT tricks you can imagine! Have fun.
RECON nmap scans For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous boxes in the Open Beta Season II.</description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy effects to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals.</description></item><item><title>Phonebook</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/phonebook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/phonebook/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Phonebook is currently active (Oct 2021) and worth 30 points.
FIRST TAKE I started up the challenge and visited the website. It is a small login form.
Looks pretty typical. Checking the source code for another look reveals a conspicuous little script:
&amp;lt;script&amp;gt; const queryString = window.location.search; if (queryString) { const urlParams = new URLSearchParams(queryString); const message = urlParams.get(&amp;#39;message&amp;#39;); if (message) { document.</description></item></channel></rss>