<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Credential Re-Use on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/credential-re-use/</link><description>Recent content in Credential Re-Use on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/credential-re-use/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GreenHorn</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/greenhorn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/greenhorn/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>GreenHorn&lt;/em> was introduced in the time between the fifth and sixth HTB seasons. It&amp;rsquo;s about a web development company that prides itself on hiring very inexperienced developers. Thankfully for us, the boss also has very bad security practices &amp;#x1f602;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon is very fast. First, recognize that there are two ports to investigate: both ports 80 and 3000 are running HTTP servers. Check them both out before doing anything else. As it turns out, one of them is hosting a git repo for the other - so finding critical sensitive details is very easy. Accessing the service on port 80, we can get a version number of the software being used. Some quick searching should lead to a CVE and a number of PoC exploits for it. Exploit the known vulnerability to gain a foothold on the system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SolarLab</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>SolarLab&lt;/em> was released as the fourth box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. Although it&amp;rsquo;s rated Medium, I would rate it more like an Easy. The box is about a company of three employees that are creating an instant messaging platform. The background is largely unimportant for the solution, though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This box takes little to no recon. Checking the SMB share will give you want you need to get started. Reading through or spidering the initial website on port 80 will lead you towards a subdomain on another port, where you will find a nice little web challenge for exploiting inadequate input validation / sanitization and a vulnerable backend PDF-generation library. It might take a little bit of determination to find exactly the vulnerable portion of this website, but once found it is quite easy to gain RCE, and immediately after grab the user flag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Download</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Download&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the eighth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em> (Half done the season now!). When &lt;em>Download&lt;/em> was released, it was originally marked as Medium - now it is Hard. I agree with this: discovering vulnerabilities on the box was quite obscure, more like a Hard difficulty box, but once you find those vulnerabilities, exploiting them is relatively easy. Gaining a foothold is the hardest part of &lt;em>Download&lt;/em>, happening in two steps: the first requires careful code analysis and possibly creating some tools of your own; the second requires a creative re-application of techniques usually used for a different type of application. For privilege escalation A bit of knowledge of &lt;em>the old ways&lt;/em> of privilege escalation will be invaluable for getting the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is &lt;em>Gofer&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. &lt;em>Gofer&lt;/em> is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work. All in all, Gofer is very pleasant to run: the creator of the box clearly put great care into constructing a whole narrative and fictional context for the box. A little bit of enumeration, a few intelligent guesses, and a good knowledge of a few web tricks will gain you foothold&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this guide, &lt;em>RegistryTwo&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the sixth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. This box truly lives up to the level of &amp;ldquo;Insane&amp;rdquo;. Every step requires a very good grasp of hacking fundamentals. &lt;em>RegistryTwo&lt;/em> features a mixture of both open-source code and APIs, and homebrew Java applications. Careful code analysis skills and a very strong Java background is essential. This box will require you to either do a bit of coding or extensively modify some existing tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in &lt;em>Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy &lt;em>effects&lt;/em> to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals. The root flag is quick, but requires wrapping your head around some cryptography concepts and formulating a customized solution to overcome the problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the very first box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. The box is hosting a webserver for a &amp;ldquo;Secret Spy Agency&amp;rdquo;. They seem to concern themselves with gathering intelligence from other agencies, but the website is mostly a tip-line: users can privately submit tips to SSA using their contact form and PGP key. The best part is, they even have a page that instructs you on proper usage of PGP &amp;#x1f609;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Busqueda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For folks like myself that have &lt;em>nada espanol&lt;/em>, it turns out &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>busqueda&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; is Spanish for &amp;ldquo;search&amp;rdquo;. It should be no surprise that this box is a search engine. Or rather, it is an aggregator of several search engines all in one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers.&lt;/strong>
&lt;strong>No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/index%20page.png" alt="index page">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a &lt;code>nmap&lt;/code> subdirectory. Then set $RADDR to my target machine&amp;rsquo;s IP, and scanned it with my typical nmap &amp;ldquo;init&amp;rdquo; scan:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soccer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/soccer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/soccer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At first, the target seems like a half-built Apache server. After a little enumeration, it seems like a single server hosting four website templates: one for music, one for interior design, one for artwork, and one that is generally-applicable.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s funny, but some of these seem like really nice templates.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The real action, as the name of the box suggests, is at the admin panel that manages the templates. It&amp;rsquo;s a site for typical web hosting tasks like managing hosts, editing DNS, adding users, etc.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>