<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/web/</link><description>Recent content in Web on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CDNio</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/cdnio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/cdnio/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION The challenge is involves a strange little webserver (using Flask running on Gunicorn) positioned behind a caching proxy (using Nginx). There is some kind of bot mechanism for crawling the site. Aside from the bot, the only relevant URLs are for:
registration login retrieving our own profile We&amp;rsquo;re free to register a user, then access our own profile info.
We can also access our own profile info. Presumably the feature to retrieve our profile is for the sake of accessing our API key?</description></item><item><title>Armaxis</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/armaxis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/armaxis/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Starting the challenge, we&amp;rsquo;re given two ports, corresponding to two components: a website and an web-based email client. The website presents a simple login/registration form, and the email client brings us straight into an inbox without any authentication:
A quick skim through the website code suggests that this email client will probably be used for password resets.
CODE ANALYSIS As usual, I like to read through the code sequentially, starting from startup/initialization code (the Dockerfile, then index.</description></item><item><title>Spellbound Servants</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/spellbound-servants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/spellbound-servants/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure about the description on this one&amp;hellip; To me, it just looks like a partially-finished storefront &amp;#x1f602;
As long as you don&amp;rsquo;t get too bogged-down with all the Flask-related code, this challenge is really easy. A bit of code analysis leads directly to the solution, which involves only a single step of deserialization to accomplish. Besides the vulnerability, this challenge presents a great example of writing a clean &amp;amp; tidy Flask server.</description></item><item><title>C O P</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/c-o-p/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/c-o-p/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION C O P (Cult of Pickles) is an Easy web challenge, involving requireing equal portions of SQLi, and deserialization, and brine. The challenge is a very minimal web app, demonstrating a bit of a &amp;ldquo;toy problem&amp;rdquo; with SQLi arising from a failure to use SQL prepared statements and sloppy Flask+Jinja2 templating code.
Achieving actual RCE is a bit challenging, but mostly because of a very strange issue. Formulation of your attack steps and writing the exploit is not too bad.</description></item><item><title>POP Restaurant</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/pop-restaurant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/pop-restaurant/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION POP Restaurant, by @khanhhnahk1, is an excellent demonstration of why secure coding practices are important. As is hinted by the name, we utilize a PHP POP chain to execute arbitrary PHP on the target.
FIRST TAKE &amp;#x1f60d; This UI is adorbs.
It&amp;rsquo;s a PHP-based web app. Besides the database interfacing code, everything looks like it&amp;rsquo;s entirely custom.
We can register a user, then start placing &amp;ldquo;orders&amp;rdquo; to the restaurant.</description></item><item><title>Spookifier</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/spookifier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/spookifier/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Spookifier is an excellent introduction to a very fun class of web vulnerabilities. It makes for a nice little &amp;ldquo;coffee break&amp;rdquo; challenge. Perfect if you don&amp;rsquo;t have much time.
FIRST TAKE Start by downloading the files. It&amp;rsquo;s a docker container with a Flask application inside. Read the code, and realize there&amp;rsquo;s only one endpoint inside.
It&amp;rsquo;s a Python Flask server and uses Mako as a template engine.
FIND THE VULN Without too much code reading, it is clear that there probably isn&amp;rsquo;t a command injection here: there&amp;rsquo;s no obvious vulnerable code that normally leads to OS command injection.</description></item><item><title>PDFy</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/pdfy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2029 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/pdfy/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION PDFy is a web challenge by the prolific @makelaris. It&amp;rsquo;s about exploiting a known vulnerability in the wkhtmltopdf application - a solution for parsing HTML and printing it into a PDF using a built-in stylesheet. Since we know the goal of this challenge was to disclose a file, it&amp;rsquo;s not overly challenging to find a vulnerability to suit our needs.
By far, the biggest obstacle on PDFy is overcoming the lack of a VPN connection.</description></item><item><title>HTTP Verb Testing</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/http-verb-testing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/http-verb-testing/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION HTTP Verbs Every HTTP request starts with a single word. 99% of the time, it&amp;rsquo;s either GET or POST. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever programmed a REST API, perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve also used PUT and DELETE. Here&amp;rsquo;s the request your browser made when visiting my website:
GET https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ HTTP/1.1 host: 4wayhandshake.github.io User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (X11; Linux x86_64; rv:109.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/115.0 Accept: text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,image/avif,image/webp,*/*;q=0.8 Accept-Language: en-US,en;q=0.5 DNT: 1 Connection: keep-alive Upgrade-Insecure-Requests: 1 Sec-Fetch-Dest: document Sec-Fetch-Mode: navigate Sec-Fetch-Site: none Sec-Fetch-User: ?</description></item><item><title>Server-side Request Forgery (SSRF)</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/ssrf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/ssrf/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Why write this? I often forget small steps about testing SSRF. It&amp;rsquo;d be good to have a checklist to remind myself of things to investigate when I find an opportunity for SSRF.
This is by no means comprehensive. If you want a longer and more detailed guide, I recommend the Hacktricks page
ADDRESS FILTER BYPASS Even if an SSRF vulnerability is present, any half-decent web app will still filter the addresses that can be requested via the SSRFable component.</description></item><item><title>Insomnia</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/insomnia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2029 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/insomnia/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Insomnia is a web challenge about bypassing a login mechanism. All source code is provided, and proper analysis of the code will yield the solution. It took me longer than I care to admit to solve this one, but frankly this challenge is more on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo;. Anyone that has any experience programming an authentication mechanism will see the flaw with minimal effort. Once it&amp;rsquo;s found, exploiting this flaw is trivial, and the flag can be obtained in a single web request.</description></item><item><title>cURL Scripting</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/curl-scripting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/curl-scripting/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Why write this? Because who needs browsers when you can just pipe curl into bash and parse with grep, sed, and awk &amp;#x1f639;
Sometimes I find myself in a circumstance where I want to do a little bit of automation/scripting with web requests, but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like writing a whole Python script for it. At least for me, a really common circumstance for me wanting to do this is when I want to automate some kind of login where I encounter a CSRF check.</description></item><item><title>Filter Bypass Techniques</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/filter-bypass/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/filter-bypass/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Why write this? Too often, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself in a situation where I needed to bypass some kind of filter and wanted a checklist to reference. However, when searching for such a checklist, I encounter two difficulties with the references I find:
Information is far too task-specific. Many are only about XSS filter evasion, or only about WAFs. There&amp;rsquo;s just too much. Many of these references have hundreds of different techniques to try.</description></item><item><title>Login Forms</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/login-forms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/login-forms/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION The moment you encounter a login form can be magical: there are so many possibilities at your fingertips&amp;hellip; did they leave some default credentials on the system? Is there an SSRF? Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a way to bypass authentication completely?
Having so many options can be both a blessing and a curse. It can be a little daunting to have to keep so many techniques in mind, and to keep your eyes open for evidence of the form&amp;rsquo;s vulnerability to each.</description></item><item><title>Web Enumeration</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/web-enumeration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/web-enumeration/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Why write this? Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve settled into a pretty good set of web enumeration techniques. As I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing more and more walkthroughs, it has started feeling quite repetetive always writing about the same web enumeration strategy. Why not skip that whole song-and-dance, and write it on a separate page that I can link to?
Most importantly, I like having a convenient reference for myself: it really speeds up recon on a box when you have exactly the right enumeration commands at your fingertips.</description></item><item><title>baby todo or not todo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/baby-todo-or-not-todo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/baby-todo-or-not-todo/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION This challenge is a docker container, coming packaged with a zip of all of the whole docker container (it&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;white box&amp;rdquo; challenge.)
Open up the source code and read through it, get a sense of how the app is supposed to work. The name of the folder indicates &amp;ldquo;broken authentication control&amp;rdquo;, so that&amp;rsquo;s probably where this is headed.
FIRST TAKE The db file schema.sql is the first file to read.</description></item><item><title>baby WAFfles order</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/baby-waffles-order/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/baby-waffles-order/</guid><description>FIRST TAKE Download the challenge files: it is a docker, showing you the source code for the whole challenge.
Obvious hint: the title of the website is xxe
Read all the source code, understand how the web app works. In essence, the challenge is an order-taking API for a fictional restaurant, taking orders for either Ice Scream or WAFfles. Orders may be submitted to /api/order as:
application/json application/xml CONVERTING REQUEST TO XML It appears that the website is configured to submit orders as json, but the endpoint will still accept xml.</description></item><item><title>Phonebook</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/phonebook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/phonebook/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Phonebook is currently active (Oct 2021) and worth 30 points.
FIRST TAKE I started up the challenge and visited the website. It is a small login form.
Looks pretty typical. Checking the source code for another look reveals a conspicuous little script:
&amp;lt;script&amp;gt; const queryString = window.location.search; if (queryString) { const urlParams = new URLSearchParams(queryString); const message = urlParams.get(&amp;#39;message&amp;#39;); if (message) { document.</description></item></channel></rss>