<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RunasCs on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/runascs/</link><description>Recent content in RunasCs on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/runascs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compiled</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I&amp;rsquo;d like to say I had a fun time with Compiled, but I really didn&amp;rsquo;t. It had several good learning moments, but also a lot of really painful and time-consuming steps. It was very much a &amp;ldquo;CVE box&amp;rdquo;.
Recon was easy. The initial nmap scans tell us almost everything we need to know. Two HTTP services are found right away, and the default script scan shows the presence of a subdomain.</description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION In my opinion, Freelancer was a very tough box. It was released as the 7th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. It&amp;rsquo;s about attacking an Active Directory environment that&amp;rsquo;s running a freelancer job market website. Solving this box requires a wide array of skills. However, while a many skills are required, none of the individual steps in the solution are painfully difficult. It is a long box though, with roughly equal amounts of labour required for foothold, the user flag, and for privilege escalation.</description></item><item><title>Crafty</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/crafty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/crafty/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Crafty is an easy-rated Windows box, released for week 6 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV Savage Lands. This box centers around exploitation of log4j - maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it &amp;#x1f602; It was a really big deal in 2021. While the disaster that ensued caused heaps of damage, very little actually changed as a result of its occurrence. If anything can be said for it, at least it stoked the international dialog on supply-chain attacks and the failing health of the open-source ecosystem.</description></item></channel></rss>