<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Default Credentials on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/default-credentials/</link><description>Recent content in Default Credentials on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/default-credentials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WifineticTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the 11th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;, &lt;em>WifineticTwo&lt;/em> was released mid-March 2024. Although it&amp;rsquo;s officially rated as medium difficulty, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely on the easier side of medium. The skills required to root this box are pretty minimal, but it does require a little &lt;em>out of the box&lt;/em> thinking. This box was a lot of fun, in the end. Take the name as a hint &amp;#x1f609;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upon starting the box, OpenPLC is the first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll notice. It&amp;rsquo;s archived software, used for turning various devices into software-based PLCs - things like Arduinos and Raspberry Pis, where you can get pin-by-pin access to inputs and outputs. Thankfully though, it also supports x86 Linux architecture, which will lead into an easy initial foothold. Just read about prior exploits for this software and you&amp;rsquo;ll have a shell in no time. First blood for the user flag on this box took less than 8 minutes. Frankly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even follow my usual recon procedure, because the exploit to gain foothold seemed readily apparent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Login Forms</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/login-forms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/login-forms/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The moment you encounter a login form can be magical: there are so many possibilities at your fingertips&amp;hellip; did they leave some &lt;em>default credentials&lt;/em> on the system? Is there an &lt;em>SSRF&lt;/em>? Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a way to &lt;em>bypass authentication&lt;/em> completely?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having so many options can be both a blessing and a curse. It can be a little daunting to have to keep so many techniques in mind, and to keep your eyes open for evidence of the form&amp;rsquo;s vulnerability to each. In an effort to keep your efforts focused and heading in the right direction, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/">strategy&lt;/a> of my favorite techniques to try on login forms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toolbox</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Continuing on with my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series, &lt;em>Toolbox&lt;/em> is the fourth box. For the previous one, see &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/buff/">my walkthrough on &lt;em>Buff&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. Unfortunately, while this box was advertised as Windows, &lt;em>it&amp;rsquo;s actually 100% Linux&lt;/em>. Yes, a little disappointing, but it&amp;rsquo;s still good practice. It might not seem like it right away, but if you have some experience with &lt;code>sqlmap&lt;/code>, then &lt;em>Toolbox&lt;/em> will be a breeze.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was very short; you are only meant to find one thing, and it appears right away. To gain a foothold, just apply a little &lt;em>ffuf-fu&lt;/em> and &lt;code>sqlmap&lt;/code> will bridge the gap. The foothold brings you straight to the user flag. From there, take a moment to fingerprint the system in front of you: a little bit of research about the system goes a long way. If you want to finish up quickly, you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to pwn the system to gain the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keeper</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/keeper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/keeper/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Keeper&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. &lt;em>Keeper&lt;/em> is a very easy box, but with a few tricks up its sleeve. Personally, I found a few aspects of this box to be a little frustrating, but in retrospect those things that I found frustrating were probably the most realistic parts of the box. While it is marked as a Linux box, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a beginner&amp;rsquo;s grasp on some Windows tools to be able to escalate to root.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenAdmin</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/openadmin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/openadmin/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At first, the target seems like a half-built Apache server. After a little enumeration, it seems like a single server hosting four website templates: one for music, one for interior design, one for artwork, and one that is generally-applicable.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s funny, but some of these seem like really nice templates.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The real action, as the name of the box suggests, is at the admin panel that manages the templates. It&amp;rsquo;s a site for typical web hosting tasks like managing hosts, editing DNS, adding users, etc.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>