<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Passing the Hash on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/passing-the-hash/</link><description>Recent content in Passing the Hash on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/passing-the-hash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forest</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/forest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/forest/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> is 100% Active Directory&lt;/strong>. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a box with no webserver and only AD is a bit like staring at a blank wall - it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know where to start with enumeration. &lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> is fantastic practice to break you out of that mindset, and help understand good methods for attacking AD environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon mostly consists of going through checklists of ways to enumerate active directory in an unauthenticated manner. It helps a lot to know a few good methods to try, and see how far that gets you. &lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> was all about being methodical and knowing when you&amp;rsquo;ve found something useful. The only thing we really need to realize during recon is that &lt;strong>Kerberos preauthentication is disabled&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MonitorsThree</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>MonitorsThree&lt;/em> was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 6, &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting addition to the &amp;ldquo;Monitors&amp;rdquo; line of boxes, all of which prominently feature the &lt;strong>Cacti&lt;/strong> monitoring tool. This box took a little bit of research to complete, but was generally on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was almost nonessential. Once you discover the &lt;code>cacti&lt;/code> subdomain, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to proceed. Fingerprint the two apps you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered, then check out the main &lt;code>monitorsthree&lt;/code> app in more detail. The site has a couple forms on it; running a popular tool to abuse these forms is enough to get you started on a foothold. From there, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover a credential leading you back to the &lt;code>cacti&lt;/code> web app. A little bit of vulnerability research goes a long way here. By exploiting a well known vulnerability (with well-documented PoC), you&amp;rsquo;ll gain an easy foothold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my opinion, &lt;em>Freelancer&lt;/em> was a very tough box. It was released as the 7th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s about attacking an Active Directory environment that&amp;rsquo;s running a freelancer job market website. Solving this box requires a wide array of skills. However, while a many skills are required, none of the individual steps in the solution are painfully difficult. It is a long box though, with roughly equal amounts of labour required for foothold, the user flag, and for privilege escalation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows PrivEsc</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/windows-privesc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/windows-privesc/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While doing the HTB box &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/love/">Love&lt;/a>&lt;/em> for my my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series, I encountered a privilege escalation technique that I had never seen. Thankfully, the technique was very clearly outlined within &lt;a href="https://tryhackme.com/room/windows10privesc">this TryHackMe room&lt;/a>. Since the room contained such a useful tip, why not go complete the whole thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="task-1">TASK 1&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="deploy-the-vm">Deploy the VM&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Connect to the VPN and click the &lt;strong>Start Machine&lt;/strong> button to start up the VM. Oddly enough, I had trouble connecting to the VPN due to the strange way &lt;code>openvpn&lt;/code> parses its arguments - I had to specify which cipher to use:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>