<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reverse Engineering on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/reverse-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Reverse Engineering on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/reverse-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Instant</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/instant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/instant/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Instant was released for week 11 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, Heist. It&amp;rsquo;s about a company that provides a money transfer service - both an app and an accompanying API. While it&amp;rsquo;s marked as &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; box, I would personally rate this one more as an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo;. The most difficult aspect is having knowledge of the correct tools to use (and a bit of determination during enumeration).
The website urges us to download an app, in the form of an Android APK.</description></item><item><title>Lantern</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Is it Linux? I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure&amp;hellip; &amp;#x1f914;
Lantern, the third box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 Heist, claims to be a Linux box, but in most respects actually it&amp;rsquo;s actually running things as one might in Windows. It isn&amp;rsquo;t until the very end of privesc to root that we find anything Linux-specific. Lantern is about a generic IT services company running a landing page and an admin panel. What made this one a little special is its extensive use of Blazor.</description></item><item><title>Intuition</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I hope that Runner got you warmed up for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, Anomalies&amp;hellip; because you&amp;rsquo;re going to need it - this one is tough! Intuition was released as the second box of the season, requiring a wide array of skills to complete. Intuition is very long: by my count, it has ten distinct steps to overcome (which classifies it as being on the harder end of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; difficulty). Interestingly though, Intuition requires very little in terms of &amp;ldquo;exploitation&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about finding and abusing simple misconfigurations/mistakes - which, I think, makes it a more realistic scenario than many HTB boxes.</description></item><item><title>Zipping</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/zipping/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/zipping/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Zipping was released just minutes ago. It was released as the tenth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The box features a fictional e-commerce site (of what some might call a &amp;ldquo;lifestyle brand&amp;rdquo; *groan*). But good news - they&amp;rsquo;re hiring! With the ability to upload your CV, get ready for some file upload shenanigans.
After initial entry, you&amp;rsquo;re presented with a very fun little reverse engineering / binex challenge.</description></item><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is Gofer is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Gofer is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work.</description></item></channel></rss>