<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MonitorsThree</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>MonitorsThree&lt;/em> was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 6, &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting addition to the &amp;ldquo;Monitors&amp;rdquo; line of boxes, all of which prominently feature the &lt;strong>Cacti&lt;/strong> monitoring tool. This box took a little bit of research to complete, but was generally on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was almost nonessential. Once you discover the &lt;code>cacti&lt;/code> subdomain, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to proceed. Fingerprint the two apps you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered, then check out the main &lt;code>monitorsthree&lt;/code> app in more detail. The site has a couple forms on it; running a popular tool to abuse these forms is enough to get you started on a foothold. From there, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover a credential leading you back to the &lt;code>cacti&lt;/code> web app. A little bit of vulnerability research goes a long way here. By exploiting a well known vulnerability (with well-documented PoC), you&amp;rsquo;ll gain an easy foothold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toolbox</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Continuing on with my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series, &lt;em>Toolbox&lt;/em> is the fourth box. For the previous one, see &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/buff/">my walkthrough on &lt;em>Buff&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. Unfortunately, while this box was advertised as Windows, &lt;em>it&amp;rsquo;s actually 100% Linux&lt;/em>. Yes, a little disappointing, but it&amp;rsquo;s still good practice. It might not seem like it right away, but if you have some experience with &lt;code>sqlmap&lt;/code>, then &lt;em>Toolbox&lt;/em> will be a breeze.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was very short; you are only meant to find one thing, and it appears right away. To gain a foothold, just apply a little &lt;em>ffuf-fu&lt;/em> and &lt;code>sqlmap&lt;/code> will bridge the gap. The foothold brings you straight to the user flag. From there, take a moment to fingerprint the system in front of you: a little bit of research about the system goes a long way. If you want to finish up quickly, you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to pwn the system to gain the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this guide, &lt;em>RegistryTwo&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the sixth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. This box truly lives up to the level of &amp;ldquo;Insane&amp;rdquo;. Every step requires a very good grasp of hacking fundamentals. &lt;em>RegistryTwo&lt;/em> features a mixture of both open-source code and APIs, and homebrew Java applications. Careful code analysis skills and a very strong Java background is essential. This box will require you to either do a bit of coding or extensively modify some existing tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MonitorsTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Upon initial enumeration, the website hosted on MonitorsTwo is something called &amp;ldquo;Cacti&amp;rdquo;, which appears to be a run-of-the-mill website management panel. However, some searching reveals that it is an open-source tool, which gives more detail about its functionality:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Cacti is a complete network graphing solution designed to harness the power of RRDtool&amp;rsquo;s data storage and graphing functionality providing the following features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Remote and local data collectors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Device discovery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automation of device and graph creation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graph and device templating&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom data collection methods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User, group and domain access controls&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers.&lt;/strong>
No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>