<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Password Cracking on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/password-cracking/</link><description>Recent content in Password Cracking on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/password-cracking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compiled</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to say I had a fun time with &lt;em>Compiled&lt;/em>, but I really didn&amp;rsquo;t. It had several good learning moments, but also a lot of really painful and time-consuming steps. It was very much a &amp;ldquo;CVE box&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was easy. The initial nmap scans tell us almost everything we need to know. Two HTTP services are found right away, and the default script scan shows the presence of a subdomain. Avoid the pitfall here of investigating one of the services too deeply without checking out the other one, too. The services are highly related to each other; it will make a lot more sense after seeing both. Remember to &lt;em>write down versions of everything&lt;/em> when you see them, and don&amp;rsquo;t skip the vuln research!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forest</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/forest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/forest/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> is 100% Active Directory&lt;/strong>. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a box with no webserver and only AD is a bit like staring at a blank wall - it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know where to start with enumeration. &lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> is fantastic practice to break you out of that mindset, and help understand good methods for attacking AD environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon mostly consists of going through checklists of ways to enumerate active directory in an unauthenticated manner. It helps a lot to know a few good methods to try, and see how far that gets you. &lt;em>Forest&lt;/em> was all about being methodical and knowing when you&amp;rsquo;ve found something useful. The only thing we really need to realize during recon is that &lt;strong>Kerberos preauthentication is disabled&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sightless</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sightless/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sightless/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Sightless&lt;/em> is the box for week 6 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s a very creative box. While each step of this box is relatively simple, the creator (&lt;strong>EmSec&lt;/strong>) throws many creative challenges at us with this one. There are a few rabbit-holes to watch out for, and it can be easy to feel a little lost while seeking privesc to root. &lt;em>Sightless&lt;/em> requires you to actually work inside some GUI applications, instead of being able to root the box solely through a terminal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MonitorsThree</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>MonitorsThree&lt;/em> was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 6, &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting addition to the &amp;ldquo;Monitors&amp;rdquo; line of boxes, all of which prominently feature the &lt;strong>Cacti&lt;/strong> monitoring tool. This box took a little bit of research to complete, but was generally on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was almost nonessential. Once you discover the &lt;code>cacti&lt;/code> subdomain, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to proceed. Fingerprint the two apps you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered, then check out the main &lt;code>monitorsthree&lt;/code> app in more detail. The site has a couple forms on it; running a popular tool to abuse these forms is enough to get you started on a foothold. From there, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover a credential leading you back to the &lt;code>cacti&lt;/code> web app. A little bit of vulnerability research goes a long way here. By exploiting a well known vulnerability (with well-documented PoC), you&amp;rsquo;ll gain an easy foothold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sea</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sea/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Sea&lt;/em> was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>. With proper recon, it&amp;rsquo;s a very short box. Perhaps they will fix it after the season ends, but this box actually comes pre-exploited: to gain foothold, all you have to do is find the exploit and use it. It&amp;rsquo;s totally doable to figure out how to exploit it yourself though - that&amp;rsquo;s the method that I&amp;rsquo;ll outline in this walkthrough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IClean</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my opinion, &lt;em>IClean&lt;/em> was a really cool box. It provides a pleasant balance of recon, exploitation, and CTF-style puzzle-solving. This box provides a more realistic web attack surface than many other boxes - there are lots of pages to explore, and many ways that one could think to attack them. I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend &lt;em>IClean&lt;/em> to anyone that wants a reasonably challenging (but not too long) web-focused box. Personally, I think this one is on the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; side of medium difficulty.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mailing</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Mailing&lt;/em> was released as the third box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. The box is initially about a mail server (although that ceases to be important after a foothold is achieved).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To gain a foothold, you need to make some major assumptions using a &amp;ldquo;guess and check&amp;rdquo; procedure that is not easily automated. The foothold is possible by means of exploiting a CVE for an application that you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure is even running on the target. Moreover, the exploit requires user interaction, which you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure is even happening.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intuition</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I hope that Runner got you warmed up for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>&amp;hellip; because you&amp;rsquo;re going to need it - this one is tough! &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> was released as the second box of the season, requiring a wide array of skills to complete. &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> is very long: by my count, it has ten distinct steps to overcome (which classifies it as being on the harder end of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; difficulty). Interestingly though, &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> requires very little in terms of &amp;ldquo;exploitation&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about finding and abusing simple misconfigurations/mistakes - which, I think, makes it a more realistic scenario than many HTB boxes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runner</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/runner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/runner/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Are you ready for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>? I sure am! &lt;em>Runner&lt;/em> is the very first box of the season. Thankfully, it&amp;rsquo;s a reasonably straightforward Linux box - rated &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; but actually more on the easy side. The box centers around a cloud-based business that offers a CI/CD solution - basically just hosting JetBrains&amp;rsquo; &lt;em>TeamCity&lt;/em> and selling it as a service. While many boxes are pretty far-removed from reality, this one was actually made from a very realistic architecture, where customers run containerized CI/CD pipelines and the service provider has some kind of management product to administer and monitor it all.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Usage</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/usage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/usage/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Usage&lt;/em> was released in the short period between HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 4 and Season 5. The target is a server hosting a small blog and a set of administrative tools to manage the server. Also, the target features pretty cool little monitoring tool called &lt;strong>Monit&lt;/strong>, and seemingly also clamAV (although it didn&amp;rsquo;t factor into the attack).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Foothold is the hardest part of &lt;em>Usage&lt;/em>. After carefully examining the target and doing web enumeration on it, one only comes to the conclusion that the attack surface is quite small. However, the few interactive elements that are present do indeed have a vulnerability. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising, considering the site runs on Laravel, but the password reset form can be exploited through SQL injection. Some careful usage of &lt;code>sqlmap&lt;/code> will do wonders here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perfection</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/perfection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/perfection/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Perfection&lt;/em> was released as the 9th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;, but I&amp;rsquo;m coming to it two weeks late. I really enjoyed this box, even though it was quite easy. I always appreciate when the box creator builds a little bit of a narrative around the box: in this case, we were dealing with a small school and the interaction between two people (shown on the About Us page) regarding the school&amp;rsquo;s computer systems. There weren&amp;rsquo;t too many distractions on this one: if you know what you&amp;rsquo;re looking at, the solution for all steps should be readily apparent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Codify</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/codify/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/codify/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Codify&lt;/em> is an easy-rated Linux box that demonstrates just how badly things can go when producing small / indie web apps in the NodeJS environment. In the modern context of tech leaning heavily on open-source projects, Codify highlights an increasingly relevant issue: &lt;em>how do we deal with open-source dependencies when those packages go stale, unmaintained, or otherwise EOL?&lt;/em> While this box was especially easy, it was an absolute delight to solve.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wordlist Generation</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/wordlist-generation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2037 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/wordlist-generation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sometimes it can be a little daunting to create custom wordlists. Generally, you either need some specialized tools, or to be well-versed in bash scripting. Another issue you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter is that wordlists tend to be large - &lt;em>very large&lt;/em>. As such, when you&amp;rsquo;re working with them, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>accidentally exceed your machine&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>memory&lt;/strong> limits&lt;/li>
&lt;li>or use up too much disk space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>waste a lot of CPU time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll try to help you overcome all these issues. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll use a mixture of specialized tools and bash scripting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bizness</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bizness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bizness/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Bizness&lt;/em>, at first glance, is a cheeky satire of the modern business landing page. It&amp;rsquo;s a website for a fictional company called BizNess that seemingly&amp;hellip; well, I can&amp;rsquo;t really tell what they do. They use a lot of fun buzz words though! &amp;#x1f60e; The entry into the server is all about attacking some well-known ERP software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Foothold on this box is a breeze. A little bit of enumeration and fingerprinting will lead to near-instantaneous success. Privilege escalation to root, however, is much more difficult. It will require you to enumerate very carefully, finding ways to tackle a system bloated with distracting configuration files, plugins, and log files everywhere. Not only that, but when you finally do find what you need, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to apply solid reasoning to take what you&amp;rsquo;ve found and transform it into escalation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Devvortex</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/devvortex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/devvortex/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Devvortex&lt;/em> is still active and worth some points. The box revolves around a fictional web development company, and their landing page. A small amount of enumeration and a check for CVEs leads directly to an easy foothold. From there, good fundamentals will allow you to achieve the User flag with ease, then the root flag with even greater ease!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This box is perfect for anyone looking to get started in HTB, or someone (like me) who wants to renew their skills after a long hiatus. The biggest danger on this box is to accidentally over-think it &amp;#x1f609;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CozyHosting</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cozyhosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cozyhosting/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Cozyhosting&lt;/em> was released as the penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season II &amp;ldquo;Hackers Clash&amp;rdquo;. The box is set up as a server hosting a &lt;code>Spring Boot&lt;/code> application, with the challenge revolving around exploiting the web app to gain an initial foothold. The box uses common vulnerabilities and is definitely one of the easier boxes of the season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon for &lt;em>Cozyhosting&lt;/em> was important. A little bit of enumeration will yield a token with which you can hijack an existing session, giving you access to an admin dashboard. The admin dashboard has functionality inside it that can lead directly into a foothold - the only trick is in realizing what&amp;rsquo;s in front of you (Burp will be very useful here). Also, knowing a few tricks for escaping strings for shell command injection might help &amp;#x1f609;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keeper</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/keeper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/keeper/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Keeper&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. &lt;em>Keeper&lt;/em> is a very easy box, but with a few tricks up its sleeve. Personally, I found a few aspects of this box to be a little frustrating, but in retrospect those things that I found frustrating were probably the most realistic parts of the box. While it is marked as a Linux box, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a beginner&amp;rsquo;s grasp on some Windows tools to be able to escalate to root.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MonitorsTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Upon initial enumeration, the website hosted on MonitorsTwo is something called &amp;ldquo;Cacti&amp;rdquo;, which appears to be a run-of-the-mill website management panel. However, some searching reveals that it is an open-source tool, which gives more detail about its functionality:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Cacti is a complete network graphing solution designed to harness the power of RRDtool&amp;rsquo;s data storage and graphing functionality providing the following features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Remote and local data collectors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Device discovery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automation of device and graph creation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graph and device templating&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom data collection methods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User, group and domain access controls&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers.&lt;/strong>
No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traverxec</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Traverxec is an older box, dating back to 2019, created by a reasonably-famous HTB user named &lt;strong>jkr&lt;/strong>. It prominently features a very minimal webserver called &lt;strong>Nostromo&lt;/strong>. Nostromo is a quick win, reinforcing some key pentesting fundamentals: checking for CVEs and vulnerability recognition while on the local system (after gaining foothold). The procedure for this box is fairly straightforward - a little Linux knowledge will grant the root flag.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I wrote this walkthrough before I had figured out a methodical and consistent way to take notes. Please excuse the haphazard formatting and brevity.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>