<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SMTP on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/smtp/</link><description>Recent content in SMTP on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/smtp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cat</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cat was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice&amp;hellip; and it was an absolute delight! If you&amp;rsquo;re searching for a fun box to try some web attacks, look no further!
Plus, what is more fitting for a web-oriented box than a website for ranking cute cat photos? &amp;#x1f431;
Recon was easy, as long as .git is in your go-to dirbusting wordlist. Once discovering the exposed .git directory, you can read through the target&amp;rsquo;s website source code.</description></item><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is Gofer is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Gofer is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work.</description></item><item><title>Trick</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/trick/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Trick appears to be a website that is under construction. At first glance, there is no functionality, but a little enumeration will reveal much more. Finding a foothold is not too difficult as long as proper enumeration techniques are followed. While this is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; box, the path to root takes a lot of creativity and forethought, and a bit of scripting. You&amp;rsquo;re fighting against a system that is trying to protect itself, but there is a way in!</description></item></channel></rss>