<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CVE on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/cve/</link><description>Recent content in CVE on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/cve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitored</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Monitored&lt;/em> was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;. As is evident from visiting the index page of the box, this one centers around Nagios, an IT administration and monitoring solution for enterprise. The documentation for Nagios XI is extremely scant, which proves to be one of the main stumbling points of this box. At least 90% of the effort for this box is spent on gaining a foothold - a moment which feels perpetually just out-of-reach. Nevertheless, this box is a hard teacher: reminding us to never give up and always &lt;em>hack harder&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Buff</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/buff/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/buff/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Buff&lt;/em> is the third Windows box in my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. For the previous one, see &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/netmon/">my walkthrough on &lt;em>Netmon&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. This box houses a web app for a fictional gym / fitness center. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly easy, but requires good Windows enumeration fundamentals. Following any reasonable pentest checklist will secure a victory on this box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon is fairly unimportant with &lt;em>Buff&lt;/em>. Foothold is achieved with hardly more than a few clicks and a CVE, and leads directly to the user flag. The root flag is a little more challenging, requiring some local enumeration on the box and application of another CVE. The solution is fairly straightforward: just stick to your checklists and you&amp;rsquo;ll grab that root flag quickly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Netmon</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/netmon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/netmon/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Netmon&lt;/em> is the second Windows box in my &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s brush up on Windows!&amp;rdquo; series. For the previous one, see &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/">my walkthrough on &lt;em>Blue&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. This box revolves around a network monitoring tool called &lt;strong>PRTG&lt;/strong>. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy, and a great reintroduction to Windows tools. Recon leads straight into the user flag, skipping any necessity of acquiring a foothold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If recon was done properly, there are only a few options to follow when seeking the root flag. Thankfully, these options have very few rabbit-holes. Keep it simple, don&amp;rsquo;t dig in your heels on any particular method, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself in possession of the root flag in no time at all! Just remember: &lt;em>while software and vulnerabilities change all the time, human habits are much less volatile&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analytics</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/analytics/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, &lt;em>Analytics&lt;/em> is still active. The box centers around a fictional analytics company that provides data analysis services using the infrastructure they&amp;rsquo;re hosting. The company is running a popular open-source analytics / BI platform. This box uses a modern architecture, reflective of how real websites run these days (when they&amp;rsquo;re on-prem).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For each step of &lt;em>Analytics&lt;/em>, the skill emphasis is placed firmly on &lt;em>enumeration&lt;/em>. Combining effective enumeration skills with some good research is well-rewarded at every step of this box. For this box, foothold, user, and root are each only a single step. Once you research the right things, it should all fall right into your lap. Have some fun with this one; use this opportunity to sharpen your enumeration toolset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bizness</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bizness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bizness/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Bizness&lt;/em>, at first glance, is a cheeky satire of the modern business landing page. It&amp;rsquo;s a website for a fictional company called BizNess that seemingly&amp;hellip; well, I can&amp;rsquo;t really tell what they do. They use a lot of fun buzz words though! &amp;#x1f60e; The entry into the server is all about attacking some well-known ERP software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Foothold on this box is a breeze. A little bit of enumeration and fingerprinting will lead to near-instantaneous success. Privilege escalation to root, however, is much more difficult. It will require you to enumerate very carefully, finding ways to tackle a system bloated with distracting configuration files, plugins, and log files everywhere. Not only that, but when you finally do find what you need, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to apply solid reasoning to take what you&amp;rsquo;ve found and transform it into escalation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Devvortex</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/devvortex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/devvortex/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Devvortex&lt;/em> is still active and worth some points. The box revolves around a fictional web development company, and their landing page. A small amount of enumeration and a check for CVEs leads directly to an easy foothold. From there, good fundamentals will allow you to achieve the User flag with ease, then the root flag with even greater ease!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This box is perfect for anyone looking to get started in HTB, or someone (like me) who wants to renew their skills after a long hiatus. The biggest danger on this box is to accidentally over-think it &amp;#x1f609;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sau</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the fourth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. Sau is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; Linux box, named after its creator, &lt;strong>sau123&lt;/strong>. At face value, the box is a server hosting a web-app for collecting and displaying HTTP requests. The user is able to define &amp;ldquo;baskets&amp;rdquo; to catch requests, where the requests and their responses can later be analyzed - including their body and headers. Sau is a well-made easy box, with a straightforward path to the end. The foothold has multiple steps, emphasizing the importance of good enumeration and research. Once foothold is gained, recognition and understanding of the underlying vulnerability will ensure a quick sprint to the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pilgrimage</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, Pilgrimage is still an Active box. It was released as the second box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. The box features a webserver, hosting an application that shrinks images uploaded by the user, halving both the width and height of the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/index.png" alt="index">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous box, &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/sandworm/walkthrough.html">Sandworm&lt;/a>. I set up a directory for the box, with a &lt;code>nmap&lt;/code> subdirectory. Then set &lt;code>$RADDR&lt;/code> to my target machine&amp;rsquo;s IP, and scanned it with a simple but broad port scan:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MonitorsTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Upon initial enumeration, the website hosted on MonitorsTwo is something called &amp;ldquo;Cacti&amp;rdquo;, which appears to be a run-of-the-mill website management panel. However, some searching reveals that it is an open-source tool, which gives more detail about its functionality:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Cacti is a complete network graphing solution designed to harness the power of RRDtool&amp;rsquo;s data storage and graphing functionality providing the following features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Remote and local data collectors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Device discovery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automation of device and graph creation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graph and device templating&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Custom data collection methods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User, group and domain access controls&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers.&lt;/strong>
No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traverxec</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Traverxec is an older box, dating back to 2019, created by a reasonably-famous HTB user named &lt;strong>jkr&lt;/strong>. It prominently features a very minimal webserver called &lt;strong>Nostromo&lt;/strong>. Nostromo is a quick win, reinforcing some key pentesting fundamentals: checking for CVEs and vulnerability recognition while on the local system (after gaining foothold). The procedure for this box is fairly straightforward - a little Linux knowledge will grant the root flag.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I wrote this walkthrough before I had figured out a methodical and consistent way to take notes. Please excuse the haphazard formatting and brevity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lame</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lame/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lame/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Lame is one of the oldest boxes on HTB. Its solution is very direct: while it is a &amp;ldquo;box&amp;rdquo;, it is actually shorter than many &amp;ldquo;challenges&amp;rdquo;. It is perfect for a beginner, or someone that just wants to brush up on some more introductory pentesting skills.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a &lt;code>nmap&lt;/code> subdirectory. Then set $RADDR to my target machine&amp;rsquo;s IP, and scanned it with my typical nmap &amp;ldquo;init&amp;rdquo; scan:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Precious is an Easy Linux box on HackTheBox, released on November 26, 2022. Its high rating and easy difficulty make it an attactive way to get back into HTB after a short hiatus. It prominently features the Ruby language, and usage of ruby gems - hence the name. While the foothold is fairly straightforward, the path to root takes a bit of thought!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/index%20page.png" alt="index page">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[04:00:40] Performing nmap initial scan:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trick</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/trick/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trick appears to be a website that is under construction. At first glance, there is no functionality, but a little enumeration will reveal much more. Finding a foothold is not too difficult as long as proper enumeration techniques are followed. While this is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; box, the path to root takes a lot of creativity and forethought, and a bit of scripting. You&amp;rsquo;re fighting against a system that is trying to protect itself, but there is a way in!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>