<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Session Hijacking on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/session-hijacking/</link><description>Recent content in Session Hijacking on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/session-hijacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cat</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cat was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice&amp;hellip; and it was an absolute delight! If you&amp;rsquo;re searching for a fun box to try some web attacks, look no further!
Plus, what is more fitting for a web-oriented box than a website for ranking cute cat photos? &amp;#x1f431;
Recon was easy, as long as .git is in your go-to dirbusting wordlist. Once discovering the exposed .git directory, you can read through the target&amp;rsquo;s website source code.</description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION In my opinion, Freelancer was a very tough box. It was released as the 7th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. It&amp;rsquo;s about attacking an Active Directory environment that&amp;rsquo;s running a freelancer job market website. Solving this box requires a wide array of skills. However, while a many skills are required, none of the individual steps in the solution are painfully difficult. It is a long box though, with roughly equal amounts of labour required for foothold, the user flag, and for privilege escalation.</description></item><item><title>IClean</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION In my opinion, IClean was a really cool box. It provides a pleasant balance of recon, exploitation, and CTF-style puzzle-solving. This box provides a more realistic web attack surface than many other boxes - there are lots of pages to explore, and many ways that one could think to attack them. I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend IClean to anyone that wants a reasonably challenging (but not too long) web-focused box. Personally, I think this one is on the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; side of medium difficulty.</description></item><item><title>CozyHosting</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cozyhosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cozyhosting/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cozyhosting was released as the penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season II &amp;ldquo;Hackers Clash&amp;rdquo;. The box is set up as a server hosting a Spring Boot application, with the challenge revolving around exploiting the web app to gain an initial foothold. The box uses common vulnerabilities and is definitely one of the easier boxes of the season.
Recon for Cozyhosting was important. A little bit of enumeration will yield a token with which you can hijack an existing session, giving you access to an admin dashboard.</description></item></channel></rss>