<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Insecure Deserialization on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/insecure-deserialization/</link><description>Recent content in Insecure Deserialization on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/insecure-deserialization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spellbound Servants</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/spellbound-servants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/spellbound-servants/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure about the description on this one&amp;hellip; To me, it just looks like a partially-finished storefront &amp;#x1f602;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As long as you don&amp;rsquo;t get too bogged-down with all the Flask-related code, this challenge is really easy. A bit of code analysis leads directly to the solution, which involves only a single step of deserialization to accomplish. Besides the vulnerability, this challenge presents a great example of writing a clean &amp;amp; tidy Flask server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pov</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pov/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pov/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>HTB released &lt;em>Pov&lt;/em> during Season IV. I didn&amp;rsquo;t play that season, so I&amp;rsquo;m coming to it a few months after. I learned a lot from this box; it really helped me polish my skills for attacking Windows using a Linux box. The pathway to the root flag is very interesting, and requires a wide array of skills. Having just completed my walkthrough for &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/">Mailing&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, this box was refreshingly straightforward: there was no guesswork, and every step led quite logically into the next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this guide, &lt;em>RegistryTwo&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the sixth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. This box truly lives up to the level of &amp;ldquo;Insane&amp;rdquo;. Every step requires a very good grasp of hacking fundamentals. &lt;em>RegistryTwo&lt;/em> features a mixture of both open-source code and APIs, and homebrew Java applications. Careful code analysis skills and a very strong Java background is essential. This box will require you to either do a bit of coding or extensively modify some existing tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Precious is an Easy Linux box on HackTheBox, released on November 26, 2022. Its high rating and easy difficulty make it an attactive way to get back into HTB after a short hiatus. It prominently features the Ruby language, and usage of ruby gems - hence the name. While the foothold is fairly straightforward, the path to root takes a bit of thought!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/index%20page.png" alt="index page">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[04:00:40] Performing nmap initial scan:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>