<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Medium on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/medium/</link><description>Recent content in Medium on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:18:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/medium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cypher</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cypher/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cypher/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Cypher&lt;/em> was released for week 8 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 7 &lt;em>Vice&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s marked as Medium difficulty, not because the individual steps were hard, but probably more due the number of steps. In my opinion, this was more of an Easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was really easy. A quick &amp;ldquo;spider&amp;rdquo; of the target website and some directory enumeration is all you&amp;rsquo;ll need. This will point you towards both the authentication endpoint and a directory that still has directory listing enabled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heal</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/heal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/heal/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I arrived at &lt;em>Heal&lt;/em> a couple months after it was released. At the face of it, &lt;em>Heal&lt;/em> is about a website that has a simple resume-building service. I never really figured out how the name &amp;ldquo;Heal&amp;rdquo; relates to the box or icon. While it was on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to do way too much recon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything you need to know from recon can be found by &amp;ldquo;spidering&amp;rdquo; the website using a web app proxy (I&amp;rsquo;ll be using ZAP in this one). From here, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover a couple of subdomains and gain an understanding of how they work. The target in front of you is actually very minimal - almost everything is offloaded onto the subdomains. If you play with the app a little, you will surely notice a moment when the server trusts some data that it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t; exploiting that is half of the battle; the other half is doing research on common files that the target&amp;rsquo;s framework uses for configuration. This will lead to a successful foothold into a web app dashboard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cat</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Cat&lt;/em> was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 &lt;em>Vice&lt;/em>&amp;hellip; and it was an absolute delight! If you&amp;rsquo;re searching for a fun box to try some web attacks, look no further!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Plus, what is more fitting for a web-oriented box than a website for ranking cute cat photos? &amp;#x1f431;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Recon was easy, as long as &lt;code>.git&lt;/code> is in your go-to dirbusting wordlist. Once discovering the exposed .git directory, you can read through the target&amp;rsquo;s website source code. Read through the source code carefully, and look for mistakes that the programmer made - there are more than one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compiled</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to say I had a fun time with &lt;em>Compiled&lt;/em>, but I really didn&amp;rsquo;t. It had several good learning moments, but also a lot of really painful and time-consuming steps. It was very much a &amp;ldquo;CVE box&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was easy. The initial nmap scans tell us almost everything we need to know. Two HTTP services are found right away, and the default script scan shows the presence of a subdomain. Avoid the pitfall here of investigating one of the services too deeply without checking out the other one, too. The services are highly related to each other; it will make a lot more sense after seeing both. Remember to &lt;em>write down versions of everything&lt;/em> when you see them, and don&amp;rsquo;t skip the vuln research!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Backfire</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/backfire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/backfire/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Backfire&lt;/em> was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7, &lt;em>Vice&lt;/em>. HTB claims this one is a &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; difficulty, but I cannot agree. Maybe the lateral movement and privesc were a &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo;, but getting the user flag was frustratingly hard. More importantly though, it was extremely niche, and required a lot of scripting to stitch together two very specific exploits into one. If you&amp;rsquo;re running this box and expecting &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; difficulty, do as I did and seek out as complete of a PoC as you can&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instant</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/instant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/instant/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Instant&lt;/em> was released for week 11 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s about a company that provides a money transfer service - both an app and an accompanying API. While it&amp;rsquo;s marked as &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; box, I would personally rate this one more as an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo;. The most difficult aspect is having knowledge of the correct tools to use (and a bit of determination during enumeration).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The website urges us to download an app, in the form of an Android APK. By reverse-engineering this app, we find some poorly-protected secrets, but we can also find a couple subdomains that were (probably) previously unknown. One is the API that the app interacts with, and the other is a Swagger instance that documents the API. By analyzing the API and using a very basic attack, we can gain an easy foothold on the system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MonitorsThree</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>MonitorsThree&lt;/em> was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 6, &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting addition to the &amp;ldquo;Monitors&amp;rdquo; line of boxes, all of which prominently feature the &lt;strong>Cacti&lt;/strong> monitoring tool. This box took a little bit of research to complete, but was generally on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was almost nonessential. Once you discover the &lt;code>cacti&lt;/code> subdomain, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to proceed. Fingerprint the two apps you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered, then check out the main &lt;code>monitorsthree&lt;/code> app in more detail. The site has a couple forms on it; running a popular tool to abuse these forms is enough to get you started on a foothold. From there, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover a credential leading you back to the &lt;code>cacti&lt;/code> web app. A little bit of vulnerability research goes a long way here. By exploiting a well known vulnerability (with well-documented PoC), you&amp;rsquo;ll gain an easy foothold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blurry</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blurry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blurry/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Blurry&lt;/em> was released as the eighth box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V, &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. This box is all about attacking an AI/ML platform called &lt;code>ClearML&lt;/code>. &lt;code>ClearML&lt;/code> is a system for orchestrating various AI/ML platforms, running models and experiments on a remote server. It has an extensive Python API, which we use repeatedly while solving this box. This box is on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo;, but was still a reasonable challenge.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IClean</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my opinion, &lt;em>IClean&lt;/em> was a really cool box. It provides a pleasant balance of recon, exploitation, and CTF-style puzzle-solving. This box provides a more realistic web attack surface than many other boxes - there are lots of pages to explore, and many ways that one could think to attack them. I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend &lt;em>IClean&lt;/em> to anyone that wants a reasonably challenging (but not too long) web-focused box. Personally, I think this one is on the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; side of medium difficulty.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SolarLab</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>SolarLab&lt;/em> was released as the fourth box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. Although it&amp;rsquo;s rated Medium, I would rate it more like an Easy. The box is about a company of three employees that are creating an instant messaging platform. The background is largely unimportant for the solution, though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This box takes little to no recon. Checking the SMB share will give you want you need to get started. Reading through or spidering the initial website on port 80 will lead you towards a subdomain on another port, where you will find a nice little web challenge for exploiting inadequate input validation / sanitization and a vulnerable backend PDF-generation library. It might take a little bit of determination to find exactly the vulnerable portion of this website, but once found it is quite easy to gain RCE, and immediately after grab the user flag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pov</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pov/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pov/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>HTB released &lt;em>Pov&lt;/em> during Season IV. I didn&amp;rsquo;t play that season, so I&amp;rsquo;m coming to it a few months after. I learned a lot from this box; it really helped me polish my skills for attacking Windows using a Linux box. The pathway to the root flag is very interesting, and requires a wide array of skills. Having just completed my walkthrough for &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/">Mailing&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, this box was refreshingly straightforward: there was no guesswork, and every step led quite logically into the next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runner</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/runner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/runner/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Are you ready for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>? I sure am! &lt;em>Runner&lt;/em> is the very first box of the season. Thankfully, it&amp;rsquo;s a reasonably straightforward Linux box - rated &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; but actually more on the easy side. The box centers around a cloud-based business that offers a CI/CD solution - basically just hosting JetBrains&amp;rsquo; &lt;em>TeamCity&lt;/em> and selling it as a service. While many boxes are pretty far-removed from reality, this one was actually made from a very realistic architecture, where customers run containerized CI/CD pipelines and the service provider has some kind of management product to administer and monitor it all.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WifineticTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the 11th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;, &lt;em>WifineticTwo&lt;/em> was released mid-March 2024. Although it&amp;rsquo;s officially rated as medium difficulty, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely on the easier side of medium. The skills required to root this box are pretty minimal, but it does require a little &lt;em>out of the box&lt;/em> thinking. This box was a lot of fun, in the end. Take the name as a hint &amp;#x1f609;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upon starting the box, OpenPLC is the first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll notice. It&amp;rsquo;s archived software, used for turning various devices into software-based PLCs - things like Arduinos and Raspberry Pis, where you can get pin-by-pin access to inputs and outputs. Thankfully though, it also supports x86 Linux architecture, which will lead into an easy initial foothold. Just read about prior exploits for this software and you&amp;rsquo;ll have a shell in no time. First blood for the user flag on this box took less than 8 minutes. Frankly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even follow my usual recon procedure, because the exploit to gain foothold seemed readily apparent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitored</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Monitored&lt;/em> was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;. As is evident from visiting the index page of the box, this one centers around Nagios, an IT administration and monitoring solution for enterprise. The documentation for Nagios XI is extremely scant, which proves to be one of the main stumbling points of this box. At least 90% of the effort for this box is spent on gaining a foothold - a moment which feels perpetually just out-of-reach. Nevertheless, this box is a hard teacher: reminding us to never give up and always &lt;em>hack harder&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows PrivEsc</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/windows-privesc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/windows-privesc/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While doing the HTB box &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/love/">Love&lt;/a>&lt;/em> for my my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series, I encountered a privilege escalation technique that I had never seen. Thankfully, the technique was very clearly outlined within &lt;a href="https://tryhackme.com/room/windows10privesc">this TryHackMe room&lt;/a>. Since the room contained such a useful tip, why not go complete the whole thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="task-1">TASK 1&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="deploy-the-vm">Deploy the VM&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Connect to the VPN and click the &lt;strong>Start Machine&lt;/strong> button to start up the VM. Oddly enough, I had trouble connecting to the VPN due to the strange way &lt;code>openvpn&lt;/code> parses its arguments - I had to specify which cipher to use:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surveillance</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/surveillance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/surveillance/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, &lt;em>Surveillance&lt;/em> is still an active box. This one is all about breaking into a fictional company called that installs and operates physical security systems, such as security cameras and door access control. &lt;em>Surveillance&lt;/em> is slightly long for a Medium box, involving many rabbit-holes and escalation between three users. However, if you keep your checklists handy and take good notes, this box won&amp;rsquo;t be too challenging.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zipping</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/zipping/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/zipping/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Zipping&lt;/em> was released just minutes ago. It was released as the tenth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. The box features a fictional e-commerce site (of what some might call a &amp;ldquo;lifestyle brand&amp;rdquo; *groan*). But good news - they&amp;rsquo;re hiring! With the ability to upload your CV, get ready for some file upload shenanigans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After initial entry, you&amp;rsquo;re presented with a very fun little reverse engineering / binex challenge. A firm grasp on linux and C fundamentals will be a huge asset for gaining the root flag. Privilege escalation was a real treat! Have fun &amp;#x1f44b;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Authority</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/authority/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Authority&lt;/em> was released as the fifth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. Is a &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; Windows box, but will serve as a formidable challenge to any players unfamiliar with Windows. &lt;em>Authority&lt;/em> features a typical Microsoft environment, including Microsoft IIS server, LDAP, Kerberos, and SMB. No SSH here! You&amp;rsquo;ll have to rely on more rudimentary remote-connection methods. This box will test your filesystem enumeration skills, but not as much as your PKI knowledge. Get ready to think like a sysadmin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the very first box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. The box is hosting a webserver for a &amp;ldquo;Secret Spy Agency&amp;rdquo;. They seem to concern themselves with gathering intelligence from other agencies, but the website is mostly a tip-line: users can privately submit tips to SSA using their contact form and PGP key. The best part is, they even have a page that instructs you on proper usage of PGP &amp;#x1f609;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>