<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Walkthroughs on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/</link><description>Recent content in Walkthroughs on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pterodactyl</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pterodactyl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pterodactyl/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Pterodactyl was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 10. It&amp;rsquo;s rated medium (which seems accurate) but by the time the box is retired it may feel more like an easy: it&amp;rsquo;s a research-heavy box, so by the time it&amp;rsquo;s retired many exploits will have been developed to specifically target this scenario, allowing those after to skip a lot of the research aspect.
Recon is pretty quick, as long as you don&amp;rsquo;t wait for the rate-limited endpoint.</description></item><item><title>Facts</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/facts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/facts/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Facts was released as the first box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 10. It&amp;rsquo;s a well-designed box with little guesswork and good fundamentals; it makes for an excellent warmup for the rest of the season.
Recon reveals two HTTP servers. The first is a website running Camaleon CMS, the other is a cloud storage utility called MinIO. Spending a few extra minutes on vulnerability research is a great idea for Facts - it&amp;rsquo;ll help you move very quickly later on.</description></item><item><title>Scepter</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/scepter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/scepter/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Taking the name as a hint, Scepter is a box involving two notable &amp;ldquo;ESC&amp;rdquo; strategies from AD CS abuse. It&amp;rsquo;s a very challenging box if you&amp;rsquo;re lacking AD manual recon experience.
Initial remote recon was pretty fast. From Nmap, we discover an NFS share hosted via Portmapper. The NFS share contains several certificates. Most of which are for disabled accounts.
Foothold involves using one of the certificates we obtained during recon.</description></item><item><title>Infiltrator</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/infiltrator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/infiltrator/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION elementum nibh tellus molestie nunc non blandit massa enim nec dui nunc mattis enim ut tellus elementum sagittis vitae et leo duis ut diam quam nulla porttitor massa id neque aliquam vestibulum morbi blandit cursus risus at ultrices mi tempus imperdiet nulla malesuada pellentesque elit eget gravida cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes nascetur ridiculus mus mauris vitae ultricies leo integer malesuada nunc vel risus commodo viverra maecenas accumsan lacus vel facilisis volutpat est velit egestas dui.</description></item><item><title>Nocturnal</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/nocturnal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/nocturnal/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Nocturnal is the first box since HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 ended. It makes for a nice ego boost after being pummeled by the last few boxes. The root blood on Nocturnal only took 21 minutes. While it took me substantially longer than that, I can confirm that this box is quite easy.
Recon is very simple. You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be impacted too negatively by skipping web enumeration altogether. However, it is important to try out the target web app and get a feel for how it works.</description></item><item><title>WhiteRabbit</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/whiterabbit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/whiterabbit/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION WhiteRabbit caps off HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7, Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s a fitting send-off to a very good season. WhiteRabbit was very fun - it was long and difficult, but at no moment did it feel aimless or guessy. In terms of raw difficulty, it genuinely took some creativity but it is easier than other &amp;ldquo;Insane&amp;rdquo; difficulty boxes I&amp;rsquo;ve tried.
Recon is very important for WhiteRabbit. It was refreshing that recon involved more than simple web app enumeration.</description></item><item><title>Haze</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/haze/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/haze/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Haze was released as the penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice. It was challenging, and has several &amp;ldquo;gotchas&amp;rdquo; built into it - thankfully, these moments are surmountable with the right set of tools. Haze is a test of both the breadth of your toolbox, and how well you know each one of your tools. Haze is true to its name: at no point during this box can you see more than a single step forward&amp;hellip; My advice is to redo Bloodhound data collection (in multiple ways) every time you move laterally to another principal.</description></item><item><title>Code</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/code/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Code was released as the 11th box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice. True to it&amp;rsquo;s name, Code is about targeting a company that develops and operates an online code editor for Python. In my opinion, it&amp;rsquo;s the easiest box of the season. By my count, there were only three steps (and four &amp;ldquo;tricks&amp;rdquo;) required to finish this Code. Regardless, I found it to be very enjoyable.
Recon was practically nonexistent.</description></item><item><title>TheFrizz</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/thefrizz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/thefrizz/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION TheFrizz was released for week 10 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice. In my opinion, it was really challenging. This one takes lots of twists and turns, but is totally doable. However, like the Magic School Bus, if you push through it and focus on learning, it will definitely teach you a few things.
Recon is pretty simple. Some nmap scanning is all that you need to identify the web app you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with.</description></item><item><title>Dog</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/dog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/dog/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Dog was released for week 8 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice. It is very short and easy. When I started the box, I wondered whether it was related to Cat from earlier in the season; it is not related, as far as I can tell. I would recommend this box to a beginner, especially someone who wants to test their recon and filesystem enumeration fundamentals.
On Dog, recon is everything.</description></item><item><title>Cypher</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cypher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cypher/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cypher was released for week 8 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 7 Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s marked as Medium difficulty, not because the individual steps were hard, but probably more due the number of steps. In my opinion, this was more of an Easy.
Recon was really easy. A quick &amp;ldquo;spider&amp;rdquo; of the target website and some directory enumeration is all you&amp;rsquo;ll need. This will point you towards both the authentication endpoint and a directory that still has directory listing enabled.</description></item><item><title>Checker</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/checker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/checker/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Checker was released for week 7 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s rated as &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo;, which seems fair and accurate. This box is not straightforward, but has very little guesswork involved, making for a very satisfying puzzle!
Recon is quick and easy. Running some easy web enumeration and clicking through the two websites with a web app proxy is pretty much sufficient. Don&amp;rsquo;t do too much fuzzing, because the box will rate-limit after a hundred or so requests.</description></item><item><title>Titanic</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/titanic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/titanic/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Titanic was released as the week 6 box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an odd box, in that the first half was very, very easy while the second half was more involved. This box forces you to explore many facets of Gitea, all the way from recon to root.
Recon is easy. We discover very quickly that there is a subdomain. Visiting that subdomain, we see it is a Gitea instance.</description></item><item><title>Heal</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/heal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/heal/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I arrived at Heal a couple months after it was released. At the face of it, Heal is about a website that has a simple resume-building service. I never really figured out how the name &amp;ldquo;Heal&amp;rdquo; relates to the box or icon. While it was on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to do way too much recon.
Everything you need to know from recon can be found by &amp;ldquo;spidering&amp;rdquo; the website using a web app proxy (I&amp;rsquo;ll be using ZAP in this one).</description></item><item><title>Cat</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cat/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cat was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice&amp;hellip; and it was an absolute delight! If you&amp;rsquo;re searching for a fun box to try some web attacks, look no further!
Plus, what is more fitting for a web-oriented box than a website for ranking cute cat photos? &amp;#x1f431;
Recon was easy, as long as .git is in your go-to dirbusting wordlist. Once discovering the exposed .git directory, you can read through the target&amp;rsquo;s website source code.</description></item><item><title>Compiled</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I&amp;rsquo;d like to say I had a fun time with Compiled, but I really didn&amp;rsquo;t. It had several good learning moments, but also a lot of really painful and time-consuming steps. It was very much a &amp;ldquo;CVE box&amp;rdquo;.
Recon was easy. The initial nmap scans tell us almost everything we need to know. Two HTTP services are found right away, and the default script scan shows the presence of a subdomain.</description></item><item><title>BigBang</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bigbang/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bigbang/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION BigBang was released as the third box of Season 7 Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s rated as Hard, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s more correctly classified as Insane. It took me roughly 35h to complete, research and all.
Recon was pretty simple, at surface level. The target is just a standard Wordpress site. Do a bit of Wordpress-specific recon to find some interesting things about the site. Try finding the interactive elements on the page, and you will quickly see a way to upload files.</description></item><item><title>Alert</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/alert/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/alert/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Alert was released between seasons 6 and 7. I came to Alert after a substantial hiatus, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did! It was pretty fun. Even though it is marked as Easy, I found the foothold challenging. Privesc to root was also very pleasant, albeit quick.
Recon is pretty simple on this one. Most of what we need can be obtained through a scan for subdomains and a crawl of the main website.</description></item><item><title>Backfire</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/backfire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/backfire/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Backfire was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7, Vice. HTB claims this one is a &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; difficulty, but I cannot agree. Maybe the lateral movement and privesc were a &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo;, but getting the user flag was frustratingly hard. More importantly though, it was extremely niche, and required a lot of scripting to stitch together two very specific exploits into one. If you&amp;rsquo;re running this box and expecting &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; difficulty, do as I did and seek out as complete of a PoC as you can&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>LinkVortex</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/linkvortex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/linkvortex/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION LinkVortex was all about the recon steps. A little bit of OSINT with a portion of web fuzzing is all that it takes. First though, we must discover the technology that the target website runs on, do a little reading on how it works, and make some educated guesses about directory structure: only then will we find the dashboard login. On the dashboard login, we discover a username oracle. Finally, after finding a vulnerable subdomain, we are able to do some .</description></item><item><title>UnderPass</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/underpass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/underpass/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION UnderPass was a nice, quick and cheerful box. A perfect choice if you have limited time but feel the itch to hack something. Kudos to the box creator, @dakkmaddy, for putting together this treat. It was released between Season 6 and 7.
Recon was pleasant, and a great reminder to always include some UDP scanning (even if it usually isn&amp;rsquo;t very useful). It was a mixture of OSINT, Web enumeration, and SNMP.</description></item><item><title>EscapeTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/escapetwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/escapetwo/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Alright! Here comes Season 7, Vice. Our first box is Windows, rated Easy. Right away, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that we&amp;rsquo;re provided a credential for this one, for the rose account. With this credential, we successfully accessed SMB shares on the sequel.htb server finding the Accounting Department which contained garbled spreadsheets that, when opened as archives and read as raw XML, revealed a list of names and credentials. One of these credentials gave access to MS-SQL, that had xp_cmdshell enabled - providing us a foothold of RCE.</description></item><item><title>Forest</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/forest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/forest/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Forest is 100% Active Directory. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a box with no webserver and only AD is a bit like staring at a blank wall - it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know where to start with enumeration. Forest is fantastic practice to break you out of that mindset, and help understand good methods for attacking AD environments.
Recon mostly consists of going through checklists of ways to enumerate active directory in an unauthenticated manner.</description></item><item><title>Chemistry</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/chemistry/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/chemistry/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Chemistry was released as the penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 6, Heist. It&amp;rsquo;s about breaking into a custom service for analyzing a scientific data file. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve seen tools like this before, where some expert in a non-tech field knows just enough coding to solve a problem for themselves? It&amp;rsquo;s admirable that people do this type of thing, but these tools are often doomed by poor security - as we&amp;rsquo;ll see in this box.</description></item><item><title>Instant</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/instant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/instant/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Instant was released for week 11 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, Heist. It&amp;rsquo;s about a company that provides a money transfer service - both an app and an accompanying API. While it&amp;rsquo;s marked as &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; box, I would personally rate this one more as an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo;. The most difficult aspect is having knowledge of the correct tools to use (and a bit of determination during enumeration).
The website urges us to download an app, in the form of an Android APK.</description></item><item><title>Sightless</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sightless/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sightless/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Sightless is the box for week 6 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 Heist. It&amp;rsquo;s a very creative box. While each step of this box is relatively simple, the creator (EmSec) throws many creative challenges at us with this one. There are a few rabbit-holes to watch out for, and it can be easy to feel a little lost while seeking privesc to root. Sightless requires you to actually work inside some GUI applications, instead of being able to root the box solely through a terminal.</description></item><item><title>MonitorsThree</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION MonitorsThree was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 6, Heist. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting addition to the &amp;ldquo;Monitors&amp;rdquo; line of boxes, all of which prominently feature the Cacti monitoring tool. This box took a little bit of research to complete, but was generally on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo;.
Recon was almost nonessential. Once you discover the cacti subdomain, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to proceed. Fingerprint the two apps you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered, then check out the main monitorsthree app in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Lantern</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Is it Linux? I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure&amp;hellip; &amp;#x1f914;
Lantern, the third box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 Heist, claims to be a Linux box, but in most respects actually it&amp;rsquo;s actually running things as one might in Windows. It isn&amp;rsquo;t until the very end of privesc to root that we find anything Linux-specific. Lantern is about a generic IT services company running a landing page and an admin panel. What made this one a little special is its extensive use of Blazor.</description></item><item><title>GreenHorn</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/greenhorn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/greenhorn/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION GreenHorn was introduced in the time between the fifth and sixth HTB seasons. It&amp;rsquo;s about a web development company that prides itself on hiring very inexperienced developers. Thankfully for us, the boss also has very bad security practices &amp;#x1f602;
Recon is very fast. First, recognize that there are two ports to investigate: both ports 80 and 3000 are running HTTP servers. Check them both out before doing anything else. As it turns out, one of them is hosting a git repo for the other - so finding critical sensitive details is very easy.</description></item><item><title>Sea</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sea/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Sea was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, Heist. With proper recon, it&amp;rsquo;s a very short box. Perhaps they will fix it after the season ends, but this box actually comes pre-exploited: to gain foothold, all you have to do is find the exploit and use it. It&amp;rsquo;s totally doable to figure out how to exploit it yourself though - that&amp;rsquo;s the method that I&amp;rsquo;ll outline in this walkthrough.</description></item><item><title>Resource</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/resource/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/resource/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Resource was released as first box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, Heist. The box was created by the famous user, 0xdf - and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint! This box establishes a whole fictional company and a narrative of the scenario, to a degree that is rare among HTB boxes. We find ourselves attacking an IT service company that is going through a period of their certificate and key management. The box is full of rabbit-holes and distractions, making it slightly frustrating but definitely a more realistic simulation than many other HTB boxes.</description></item><item><title>PermX</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/permx/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/permx/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION PermX is about exploiting a learning management system called Chamilo. The box was pretty easy, and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take long to finish.
Recon mostly involves uncovering a couple subdomains. One of them is the usual, obvious subdomain, but the other is a bit more odd. Accessing the &amp;ldquo;more odd&amp;rdquo; subdomain allows you to know the name of the CMS you&amp;rsquo;re up against. Applying a little directory enumeration will reveal that you can actually access several directories in &amp;ldquo;file browser&amp;rdquo; mode, basically eliminating the need to do any file enumeration.</description></item><item><title>BoardLight</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/boardlight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/boardlight/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION BoardLight was the 6th box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. It&amp;rsquo;s an easy Linux box, focused on a web hosting platform. As far as I can tell, its name and icon have nothing to do with the box itself. Unfortunately, I was away when the box was released, and kicking myself for it - it would have been great to have such easy points on the scoreboard!
Recon is very quick.</description></item><item><title>Editorial</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Editorial was released for week 9 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V: Anomalies. With only three steps involved in its solution, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the easiest boxes in the season so far. That being said, twice on this box I ended up kicking myself for having not done something that later seemed obvious, so perhaps Editorial teaches us a lesson in a more subtle way.
There is basically no recon involved in Editorial.</description></item><item><title>Blurry</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blurry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blurry/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Blurry was released as the eighth box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V, Anomalies. This box is all about attacking an AI/ML platform called ClearML. ClearML is a system for orchestrating various AI/ML platforms, running models and experiments on a remote server. It has an extensive Python API, which we use repeatedly while solving this box. This box is on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo;, but was still a reasonable challenge.</description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION In my opinion, Freelancer was a very tough box. It was released as the 7th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. It&amp;rsquo;s about attacking an Active Directory environment that&amp;rsquo;s running a freelancer job market website. Solving this box requires a wide array of skills. However, while a many skills are required, none of the individual steps in the solution are painfully difficult. It is a long box though, with roughly equal amounts of labour required for foothold, the user flag, and for privilege escalation.</description></item><item><title>IClean</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/iclean/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION In my opinion, IClean was a really cool box. It provides a pleasant balance of recon, exploitation, and CTF-style puzzle-solving. This box provides a more realistic web attack surface than many other boxes - there are lots of pages to explore, and many ways that one could think to attack them. I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend IClean to anyone that wants a reasonably challenging (but not too long) web-focused box. Personally, I think this one is on the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; side of medium difficulty.</description></item><item><title>SolarLab</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION SolarLab was released as the fourth box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. Although it&amp;rsquo;s rated Medium, I would rate it more like an Easy. The box is about a company of three employees that are creating an instant messaging platform. The background is largely unimportant for the solution, though.
This box takes little to no recon. Checking the SMB share will give you want you need to get started. Reading through or spidering the initial website on port 80 will lead you towards a subdomain on another port, where you will find a nice little web challenge for exploiting inadequate input validation / sanitization and a vulnerable backend PDF-generation library.</description></item><item><title>Pov</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pov/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pov/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION HTB released Pov during Season IV. I didn&amp;rsquo;t play that season, so I&amp;rsquo;m coming to it a few months after. I learned a lot from this box; it really helped me polish my skills for attacking Windows using a Linux box. The pathway to the root flag is very interesting, and requires a wide array of skills. Having just completed my walkthrough for Mailing, this box was refreshingly straightforward: there was no guesswork, and every step led quite logically into the next.</description></item><item><title>Mailing</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/mailing/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Mailing was released as the third box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, Anomalies. The box is initially about a mail server (although that ceases to be important after a foothold is achieved).
To gain a foothold, you need to make some major assumptions using a &amp;ldquo;guess and check&amp;rdquo; procedure that is not easily automated. The foothold is possible by means of exploiting a CVE for an application that you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure is even running on the target.</description></item><item><title>Intuition</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I hope that Runner got you warmed up for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, Anomalies&amp;hellip; because you&amp;rsquo;re going to need it - this one is tough! Intuition was released as the second box of the season, requiring a wide array of skills to complete. Intuition is very long: by my count, it has ten distinct steps to overcome (which classifies it as being on the harder end of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; difficulty). Interestingly though, Intuition requires very little in terms of &amp;ldquo;exploitation&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about finding and abusing simple misconfigurations/mistakes - which, I think, makes it a more realistic scenario than many HTB boxes.</description></item><item><title>Runner</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/runner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/runner/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Are you ready for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, Anomalies? I sure am! Runner is the very first box of the season. Thankfully, it&amp;rsquo;s a reasonably straightforward Linux box - rated &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; but actually more on the easy side. The box centers around a cloud-based business that offers a CI/CD solution - basically just hosting JetBrains&amp;rsquo; TeamCity and selling it as a service. While many boxes are pretty far-removed from reality, this one was actually made from a very realistic architecture, where customers run containerized CI/CD pipelines and the service provider has some kind of management product to administer and monitor it all.</description></item><item><title>Usage</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/usage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/usage/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Usage was released in the short period between HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 4 and Season 5. The target is a server hosting a small blog and a set of administrative tools to manage the server. Also, the target features pretty cool little monitoring tool called Monit, and seemingly also clamAV (although it didn&amp;rsquo;t factor into the attack).
Foothold is the hardest part of Usage. After carefully examining the target and doing web enumeration on it, one only comes to the conclusion that the attack surface is quite small.</description></item><item><title>Crafty</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/crafty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/crafty/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Crafty is an easy-rated Windows box, released for week 6 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV Savage Lands. This box centers around exploitation of log4j - maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it &amp;#x1f602; It was a really big deal in 2021. While the disaster that ensued caused heaps of damage, very little actually changed as a result of its occurrence. If anything can be said for it, at least it stoked the international dialog on supply-chain attacks and the failing health of the open-source ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Headless</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/headless/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/headless/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION The penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV Savage Lands, released for week 12, is Headless. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been participating in the season, this is one of the few boxes that I attempted within the 1 week limit. It was totally worth it! This box is an absolute delight, and I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it enough. There aren&amp;rsquo;t any rabbit-holes on this one, and most of the effort will simply be to gain a foothold.</description></item><item><title>Perfection</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/perfection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/perfection/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Perfection was released as the 9th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;, but I&amp;rsquo;m coming to it two weeks late. I really enjoyed this box, even though it was quite easy. I always appreciate when the box creator builds a little bit of a narrative around the box: in this case, we were dealing with a small school and the interaction between two people (shown on the About Us page) regarding the school&amp;rsquo;s computer systems.</description></item><item><title>WifineticTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/wifinetictwo/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION As the 11th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;, WifineticTwo was released mid-March 2024. Although it&amp;rsquo;s officially rated as medium difficulty, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely on the easier side of medium. The skills required to root this box are pretty minimal, but it does require a little out of the box thinking. This box was a lot of fun, in the end. Take the name as a hint &amp;#x1f609;
Upon starting the box, OpenPLC is the first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll notice.</description></item><item><title>Monitored</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Monitored was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;. As is evident from visiting the index page of the box, this one centers around Nagios, an IT administration and monitoring solution for enterprise. The documentation for Nagios XI is extremely scant, which proves to be one of the main stumbling points of this box. At least 90% of the effort for this box is spent on gaining a foothold - a moment which feels perpetually just out-of-reach.</description></item><item><title>Love</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/love/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION It&amp;rsquo;s been a week, but now it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back into my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. Love is the fifth box, following Toolbox. This box was pretty interesting, definitely worth checking out. I really enjoyed that it avoided the whole &amp;ldquo;Find the CVE and exploit it&amp;rdquo; pattern that many Easy boxes use.
It revolves around a &amp;ldquo;File Scanner&amp;rdquo; web app with some terrible security misconfigurations and mistakes.</description></item><item><title>Toolbox</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Continuing on with my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series, Toolbox is the fourth box. For the previous one, see my walkthrough on Buff. Unfortunately, while this box was advertised as Windows, it&amp;rsquo;s actually 100% Linux. Yes, a little disappointing, but it&amp;rsquo;s still good practice. It might not seem like it right away, but if you have some experience with sqlmap, then Toolbox will be a breeze.
Recon was very short; you are only meant to find one thing, and it appears right away.</description></item><item><title>Surveillance</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/surveillance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/surveillance/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Surveillance is still an active box. This one is all about breaking into a fictional company called that installs and operates physical security systems, such as security cameras and door access control. Surveillance is slightly long for a Medium box, involving many rabbit-holes and escalation between three users. However, if you keep your checklists handy and take good notes, this box won&amp;rsquo;t be too challenging.</description></item><item><title>Codify</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/codify/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/codify/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Codify is an easy-rated Linux box that demonstrates just how badly things can go when producing small / indie web apps in the NodeJS environment. In the modern context of tech leaning heavily on open-source projects, Codify highlights an increasingly relevant issue: how do we deal with open-source dependencies when those packages go stale, unmaintained, or otherwise EOL? While this box was especially easy, it was an absolute delight to solve.</description></item><item><title>Buff</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/buff/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/buff/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Buff is the third Windows box in my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. For the previous one, see my walkthrough on Netmon. This box houses a web app for a fictional gym / fitness center. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly easy, but requires good Windows enumeration fundamentals. Following any reasonable pentest checklist will secure a victory on this box.
Recon is fairly unimportant with Buff. Foothold is achieved with hardly more than a few clicks and a CVE, and leads directly to the user flag.</description></item><item><title>Netmon</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/netmon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/netmon/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Netmon is the second Windows box in my &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s brush up on Windows!&amp;rdquo; series. For the previous one, see my walkthrough on Blue. This box revolves around a network monitoring tool called PRTG. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy, and a great reintroduction to Windows tools. Recon leads straight into the user flag, skipping any necessity of acquiring a foothold.
If recon was done properly, there are only a few options to follow when seeking the root flag.</description></item><item><title>Blue</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/blue/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Blue is a retired Windows box, the first box in my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. It ranks as one of the easiest Windows boxes. I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a whole spree of boxes to try to brush up on my Windows technique. In the end, this box was more of an exercise in trying a whole bunch of exploits and dealing with really messed-up python environments.
tldr; If you&amp;rsquo;re doing this box in 2024 or later, go straight to a more recent version of the exploit.</description></item><item><title>Analytics</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/analytics/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Analytics is still active. The box centers around a fictional analytics company that provides data analysis services using the infrastructure they&amp;rsquo;re hosting. The company is running a popular open-source analytics / BI platform. This box uses a modern architecture, reflective of how real websites run these days (when they&amp;rsquo;re on-prem).
For each step of Analytics, the skill emphasis is placed firmly on enumeration.</description></item><item><title>Bizness</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bizness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bizness/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Bizness, at first glance, is a cheeky satire of the modern business landing page. It&amp;rsquo;s a website for a fictional company called BizNess that seemingly&amp;hellip; well, I can&amp;rsquo;t really tell what they do. They use a lot of fun buzz words though! &amp;#x1f60e; The entry into the server is all about attacking some well-known ERP software.
Foothold on this box is a breeze. A little bit of enumeration and fingerprinting will lead to near-instantaneous success.</description></item><item><title>Devvortex</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/devvortex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/devvortex/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Currently, Devvortex is still active and worth some points. The box revolves around a fictional web development company, and their landing page. A small amount of enumeration and a check for CVEs leads directly to an easy foothold. From there, good fundamentals will allow you to achieve the User flag with ease, then the root flag with even greater ease!
This box is perfect for anyone looking to get started in HTB, or someone (like me) who wants to renew their skills after a long hiatus.</description></item><item><title>CozyHosting</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cozyhosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cozyhosting/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cozyhosting was released as the penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season II &amp;ldquo;Hackers Clash&amp;rdquo;. The box is set up as a server hosting a Spring Boot application, with the challenge revolving around exploiting the web app to gain an initial foothold. The box uses common vulnerabilities and is definitely one of the easier boxes of the season.
Recon for Cozyhosting was important. A little bit of enumeration will yield a token with which you can hijack an existing session, giving you access to an admin dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Zipping</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/zipping/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/zipping/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Zipping was released just minutes ago. It was released as the tenth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The box features a fictional e-commerce site (of what some might call a &amp;ldquo;lifestyle brand&amp;rdquo; *groan*). But good news - they&amp;rsquo;re hiring! With the ability to upload your CV, get ready for some file upload shenanigans.
After initial entry, you&amp;rsquo;re presented with a very fun little reverse engineering / binex challenge.</description></item><item><title>Cybermonday</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Cybermondaywas just released! It is the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The site is a fictional e-commerce site. This box will test your knowledge of SQL, broken authentication, and definitely all the JWT tricks you can imagine! Have fun.
RECON nmap scans For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous boxes in the Open Beta Season II.</description></item><item><title>Keeper</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/keeper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/keeper/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Currently, Keeper is still active. It was released as the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Keeper is a very easy box, but with a few tricks up its sleeve. Personally, I found a few aspects of this box to be a little frustrating, but in retrospect those things that I found frustrating were probably the most realistic parts of the box. While it is marked as a Linux box, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a beginner&amp;rsquo;s grasp on some Windows tools to be able to escalate to root.</description></item><item><title>Download</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Currently, Download is still active. It was released as the eighth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II (Half done the season now!). When Download was released, it was originally marked as Medium - now it is Hard. I agree with this: discovering vulnerabilities on the box was quite obscure, more like a Hard difficulty box, but once you find those vulnerabilities, exploiting them is relatively easy. Gaining a foothold is the hardest part of Download, happening in two steps: the first requires careful code analysis and possibly creating some tools of your own; the second requires a creative re-application of techniques usually used for a different type of application.</description></item><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is Gofer is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Gofer is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work.</description></item><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this guide, RegistryTwo is still active. It was released as the sixth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. This box truly lives up to the level of &amp;ldquo;Insane&amp;rdquo;. Every step requires a very good grasp of hacking fundamentals. RegistryTwo features a mixture of both open-source code and APIs, and homebrew Java applications. Careful code analysis skills and a very strong Java background is essential.</description></item><item><title>Authority</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/authority/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/authority/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Authority was released as the fifth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Is a &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; Windows box, but will serve as a formidable challenge to any players unfamiliar with Windows. Authority features a typical Microsoft environment, including Microsoft IIS server, LDAP, Kerberos, and SMB. No SSH here! You&amp;rsquo;ll have to rely on more rudimentary remote-connection methods. This box will test your filesystem enumeration skills, but not as much as your PKI knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Sau</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the fourth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Sau is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; Linux box, named after its creator, sau123. At face value, the box is a server hosting a web-app for collecting and displaying HTTP requests. The user is able to define &amp;ldquo;baskets&amp;rdquo; to catch requests, where the requests and their responses can later be analyzed - including their body and headers.</description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy effects to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals.</description></item><item><title>Pilgrimage</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Pilgrimage is still an Active box. It was released as the second box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The box features a webserver, hosting an application that shrinks images uploaded by the user, halving both the width and height of the image.
RECON For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous box, Sandworm. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item><item><title>Sandworm</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sandworm/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the very first box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The box is hosting a webserver for a &amp;ldquo;Secret Spy Agency&amp;rdquo;. They seem to concern themselves with gathering intelligence from other agencies, but the website is mostly a tip-line: users can privately submit tips to SSA using their contact form and PGP key.</description></item><item><title>MonitorsTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Upon initial enumeration, the website hosted on MonitorsTwo is something called &amp;ldquo;Cacti&amp;rdquo;, which appears to be a run-of-the-mill website management panel. However, some searching reveals that it is an open-source tool, which gives more detail about its functionality:
Cacti is a complete network graphing solution designed to harness the power of RRDtool&amp;rsquo;s data storage and graphing functionality providing the following features:
Remote and local data collectors Device discovery Automation of device and graph creation Graph and device templating Custom data collection methods User, group and domain access controls Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers.</description></item><item><title>Traverxec</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/traverxec/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Traverxec is an older box, dating back to 2019, created by a reasonably-famous HTB user named jkr. It prominently features a very minimal webserver called Nostromo. Nostromo is a quick win, reinforcing some key pentesting fundamentals: checking for CVEs and vulnerability recognition while on the local system (after gaining foothold). The procedure for this box is fairly straightforward - a little Linux knowledge will grant the root flag.
I wrote this walkthrough before I had figured out a methodical and consistent way to take notes.</description></item><item><title>Busqueda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION For folks like myself that have nada espanol, it turns out &amp;ldquo;busqueda&amp;rdquo; is Spanish for &amp;ldquo;search&amp;rdquo;. It should be no surprise that this box is a search engine. Or rather, it is an aggregator of several search engines all in one.
Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers. No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.
RECON I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item><item><title>Soccer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/soccer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/soccer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At first, the target seems like a half-built Apache server. After a little enumeration, it seems like a single server hosting four website templates: one for music, one for interior design, one for artwork, and one that is generally-applicable.
It&amp;rsquo;s funny, but some of these seem like really nice templates.
The real action, as the name of the box suggests, is at the admin panel that manages the templates. It&amp;rsquo;s a site for typical web hosting tasks like managing hosts, editing DNS, adding users, etc.</description></item><item><title>OpenAdmin</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/openadmin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/openadmin/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At first, the target seems like a half-built Apache server. After a little enumeration, it seems like a single server hosting four website templates: one for music, one for interior design, one for artwork, and one that is generally-applicable.
It&amp;rsquo;s funny, but some of these seem like really nice templates.
The real action, as the name of the box suggests, is at the admin panel that manages the templates. It&amp;rsquo;s a site for typical web hosting tasks like managing hosts, editing DNS, adding users, etc.</description></item><item><title>Bashed</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bashed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bashed/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Bashed features an infosec developer&amp;rsquo;s blog. Seemingly, the blog has just one article. That article shows a pretty huge hint for how to complete the box. Bashed is a fairly easy box, but requires a bit of careful observation after obtaining a foothold. As usual, a basic understanding of linux is an asset.
RECON I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item><item><title>Lame</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lame/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lame/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Lame is one of the oldest boxes on HTB. Its solution is very direct: while it is a &amp;ldquo;box&amp;rdquo;, it is actually shorter than many &amp;ldquo;challenges&amp;rdquo;. It is perfect for a beginner, or someone that just wants to brush up on some more introductory pentesting skills.
RECON I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory. Then set $RADDR to my target machine&amp;rsquo;s IP, and scanned it with my typical nmap &amp;ldquo;init&amp;rdquo; scan:</description></item><item><title>Precious</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/precious/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Precious is an Easy Linux box on HackTheBox, released on November 26, 2022. Its high rating and easy difficulty make it an attactive way to get back into HTB after a short hiatus. It prominently features the Ruby language, and usage of ruby gems - hence the name. While the foothold is fairly straightforward, the path to root takes a bit of thought!
RECON [04:00:40] Performing nmap initial scan:</description></item><item><title>RedPanda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/redpanda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/redpanda/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Red Panda is a hilariously cute website that acts as an index for a bunch of photos of red pandas. The red panda photos each have an author marked on them.
When a user visits the site, they may use the search bar to view the photos. When they do, it increments a view counter for that photo. Part of the site describes that the author who contributed the photo is then credited on a per-view basis.</description></item><item><title>Trick</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/trick/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/trick/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Trick appears to be a website that is under construction. At first glance, there is no functionality, but a little enumeration will reveal much more. Finding a foothold is not too difficult as long as proper enumeration techniques are followed. While this is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; box, the path to root takes a lot of creativity and forethought, and a bit of scripting. You&amp;rsquo;re fighting against a system that is trying to protect itself, but there is a way in!</description></item><item><title>Horizontall (images only)</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/horizontall/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/horizontall/</guid><description>Introduction This walkthrough is just a series of screenshots showing how I got through the box. 🤷‍♂ I did this box before I really worked out a process for recording my work effectively. Sorry!
If I find the time, I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to this and try to document it properly.
Walkthrough These are the notes I left for myself:
Found login page at http://api-prod.horizontall.htb/admin/auth/login I could brute-force the login just with ffuf Or I could try using the OpenSSH user enumeration CVE to obtain a list of users first?</description></item></channel></rss>