<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OverlayFS on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/overlayfs/</link><description>Recent content in OverlayFS on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 22:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/overlayfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analytics</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/analytics/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Analytics is still active. The box centers around a fictional analytics company that provides data analysis services using the infrastructure they&amp;rsquo;re hosting. The company is running a popular open-source analytics / BI platform. This box uses a modern architecture, reflective of how real websites run these days (when they&amp;rsquo;re on-prem).
For each step of Analytics, the skill emphasis is placed firmly on enumeration.</description></item><item><title>MonitorsTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorstwo/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Upon initial enumeration, the website hosted on MonitorsTwo is something called &amp;ldquo;Cacti&amp;rdquo;, which appears to be a run-of-the-mill website management panel. However, some searching reveals that it is an open-source tool, which gives more detail about its functionality:
Cacti is a complete network graphing solution designed to harness the power of RRDtool&amp;rsquo;s data storage and graphing functionality providing the following features:
Remote and local data collectors Device discovery Automation of device and graph creation Graph and device templating Custom data collection methods User, group and domain access controls Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers.</description></item></channel></rss>