<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Insane on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/insane/</link><description>Recent content in Insane on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/insane/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infiltrator</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/infiltrator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/infiltrator/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION elementum nibh tellus molestie nunc non blandit massa enim nec dui nunc mattis enim ut tellus elementum sagittis vitae et leo duis ut diam quam nulla porttitor massa id neque aliquam vestibulum morbi blandit cursus risus at ultrices mi tempus imperdiet nulla malesuada pellentesque elit eget gravida cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes nascetur ridiculus mus mauris vitae ultricies leo integer malesuada nunc vel risus commodo viverra maecenas accumsan lacus vel facilisis volutpat est velit egestas dui.</description></item><item><title>WhiteRabbit</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/whiterabbit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/whiterabbit/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION WhiteRabbit caps off HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7, Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s a fitting send-off to a very good season. WhiteRabbit was very fun - it was long and difficult, but at no moment did it feel aimless or guessy. In terms of raw difficulty, it genuinely took some creativity but it is easier than other &amp;ldquo;Insane&amp;rdquo; difficulty boxes I&amp;rsquo;ve tried.
Recon is very important for WhiteRabbit. It was refreshing that recon involved more than simple web app enumeration.</description></item><item><title>RegistryTwo</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/registrytwo/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this guide, RegistryTwo is still active. It was released as the sixth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. This box truly lives up to the level of &amp;ldquo;Insane&amp;rdquo;. Every step requires a very good grasp of hacking fundamentals. RegistryTwo features a mixture of both open-source code and APIs, and homebrew Java applications. Careful code analysis skills and a very strong Java background is essential.</description></item></channel></rss>