<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Flask on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/flask/</link><description>Recent content in Flask on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 22:07:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/flask/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Titanic</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/titanic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/titanic/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Titanic was released as the week 6 box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an odd box, in that the first half was very, very easy while the second half was more involved. This box forces you to explore many facets of Gitea, all the way from recon to root.
Recon is easy. We discover very quickly that there is a subdomain. Visiting that subdomain, we see it is a Gitea instance.</description></item><item><title>C O P</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/c-o-p/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ctf/c-o-p/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION C O P (Cult of Pickles) is an Easy web challenge, involving requireing equal portions of SQLi, and deserialization, and brine. The challenge is a very minimal web app, demonstrating a bit of a &amp;ldquo;toy problem&amp;rdquo; with SQLi arising from a failure to use SQL prepared statements and sloppy Flask+Jinja2 templating code.
Achieving actual RCE is a bit challenging, but mostly because of a very strange issue. Formulation of your attack steps and writing the exploit is not too bad.</description></item><item><title>HTTP Verb Testing</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/http-verb-testing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/http-verb-testing/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION HTTP Verbs Every HTTP request starts with a single word. 99% of the time, it&amp;rsquo;s either GET or POST. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever programmed a REST API, perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve also used PUT and DELETE. Here&amp;rsquo;s the request your browser made when visiting my website:
GET https://4wayhandshake.github.io/ HTTP/1.1 host: 4wayhandshake.github.io User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (X11; Linux x86_64; rv:109.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/115.0 Accept: text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,image/avif,image/webp,*/*;q=0.8 Accept-Language: en-US,en;q=0.5 DNT: 1 Connection: keep-alive Upgrade-Insecure-Requests: 1 Sec-Fetch-Dest: document Sec-Fetch-Mode: navigate Sec-Fetch-Site: none Sec-Fetch-User: ?</description></item></channel></rss>