<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SQLi (Blind) on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/sqli-blind/</link><description>Recent content in SQLi (Blind) on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/sqli-blind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitored</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Monitored was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;. As is evident from visiting the index page of the box, this one centers around Nagios, an IT administration and monitoring solution for enterprise. The documentation for Nagios XI is extremely scant, which proves to be one of the main stumbling points of this box. At least 90% of the effort for this box is spent on gaining a foothold - a moment which feels perpetually just out-of-reach.</description></item><item><title>Toolbox</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Continuing on with my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series, Toolbox is the fourth box. For the previous one, see my walkthrough on Buff. Unfortunately, while this box was advertised as Windows, it&amp;rsquo;s actually 100% Linux. Yes, a little disappointing, but it&amp;rsquo;s still good practice. It might not seem like it right away, but if you have some experience with sqlmap, then Toolbox will be a breeze.
Recon was very short; you are only meant to find one thing, and it appears right away.</description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy effects to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals.</description></item><item><title>Soccer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/soccer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/soccer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At first, the target seems like a half-built Apache server. After a little enumeration, it seems like a single server hosting four website templates: one for music, one for interior design, one for artwork, and one that is generally-applicable.
It&amp;rsquo;s funny, but some of these seem like really nice templates.
The real action, as the name of the box suggests, is at the admin panel that manages the templates. It&amp;rsquo;s a site for typical web hosting tasks like managing hosts, editing DNS, adding users, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>