<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compiled</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I&amp;rsquo;d like to say I had a fun time with Compiled, but I really didn&amp;rsquo;t. It had several good learning moments, but also a lot of really painful and time-consuming steps. It was very much a &amp;ldquo;CVE box&amp;rdquo;.
Recon was easy. The initial nmap scans tell us almost everything we need to know. Two HTTP services are found right away, and the default script scan shows the presence of a subdomain.</description></item><item><title>LinkVortex</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/linkvortex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/linkvortex/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION LinkVortex was all about the recon steps. A little bit of OSINT with a portion of web fuzzing is all that it takes. First though, we must discover the technology that the target website runs on, do a little reading on how it works, and make some educated guesses about directory structure: only then will we find the dashboard login. On the dashboard login, we discover a username oracle. Finally, after finding a vulnerable subdomain, we are able to do some .</description></item><item><title>Editorial</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Editorial was released for week 9 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V: Anomalies. With only three steps involved in its solution, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the easiest boxes in the season so far. That being said, twice on this box I ended up kicking myself for having not done something that later seemed obvious, so perhaps Editorial teaches us a lesson in a more subtle way.
There is basically no recon involved in Editorial.</description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy effects to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals.</description></item><item><title>Pilgrimage</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Pilgrimage is still an Active box. It was released as the second box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The box features a webserver, hosting an application that shrinks images uploaded by the user, halving both the width and height of the image.
RECON For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous box, Sandworm. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item><item><title>Busqueda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION For folks like myself that have nada espanol, it turns out &amp;ldquo;busqueda&amp;rdquo; is Spanish for &amp;ldquo;search&amp;rdquo;. It should be no surprise that this box is a search engine. Or rather, it is an aggregator of several search engines all in one.
Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers. No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.
RECON I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item></channel></rss>