<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compiled</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/compiled/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to say I had a fun time with &lt;em>Compiled&lt;/em>, but I really didn&amp;rsquo;t. It had several good learning moments, but also a lot of really painful and time-consuming steps. It was very much a &amp;ldquo;CVE box&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was easy. The initial nmap scans tell us almost everything we need to know. Two HTTP services are found right away, and the default script scan shows the presence of a subdomain. Avoid the pitfall here of investigating one of the services too deeply without checking out the other one, too. The services are highly related to each other; it will make a lot more sense after seeing both. Remember to &lt;em>write down versions of everything&lt;/em> when you see them, and don&amp;rsquo;t skip the vuln research!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Editorial</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em> was released for week 9 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V: &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. With only three steps involved in its solution, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the easiest boxes in the season so far. That being said, twice on this box I ended up kicking myself for having not done something that later seemed obvious, so perhaps &lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em> teaches us a lesson in a more subtle way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is basically no recon involved in &lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em>. Identify the ports, add the domain to your &lt;code>/etc/hosts&lt;/code>, and explore the website. The website only has three pages, so you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly locate the component to attack. From there, you&amp;rsquo;ll find out that this component can be used for SSRF. Follow &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/ssrf/">my SSRF checklist&lt;/a> (Disclaimer: it&amp;rsquo;s a work-in-progress) to expedite things a little. Once you interact with the internally-accessible server via the SSRF, you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly discover some credentials. Use those to gain a foothold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in &lt;em>Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy &lt;em>effects&lt;/em> to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals. The root flag is quick, but requires wrapping your head around some cryptography concepts and formulating a customized solution to overcome the problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pilgrimage</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, Pilgrimage is still an Active box. It was released as the second box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. The box features a webserver, hosting an application that shrinks images uploaded by the user, halving both the width and height of the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/pilgrimage/index.png" alt="index">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous box, &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/sandworm/walkthrough.html">Sandworm&lt;/a>. I set up a directory for the box, with a &lt;code>nmap&lt;/code> subdirectory. Then set &lt;code>$RADDR&lt;/code> to my target machine&amp;rsquo;s IP, and scanned it with a simple but broad port scan:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Busqueda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For folks like myself that have &lt;em>nada espanol&lt;/em>, it turns out &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>busqueda&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; is Spanish for &amp;ldquo;search&amp;rdquo;. It should be no surprise that this box is a search engine. Or rather, it is an aggregator of several search engines all in one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers.&lt;/strong>
&lt;strong>No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/index%20page.png" alt="index page">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a &lt;code>nmap&lt;/code> subdirectory. Then set $RADDR to my target machine&amp;rsquo;s IP, and scanned it with my typical nmap &amp;ldquo;init&amp;rdquo; scan:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>