<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Command Injection on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/command-injection/</link><description>Recent content in Command Injection on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/command-injection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sightless</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sightless/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sightless/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Sightless is the box for week 6 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 Heist. It&amp;rsquo;s a very creative box. While each step of this box is relatively simple, the creator (EmSec) throws many creative challenges at us with this one. There are a few rabbit-holes to watch out for, and it can be easy to feel a little lost while seeking privesc to root. Sightless requires you to actually work inside some GUI applications, instead of being able to root the box solely through a terminal.</description></item><item><title>SolarLab</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/solarlab/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION SolarLab was released as the fourth box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. Although it&amp;rsquo;s rated Medium, I would rate it more like an Easy. The box is about a company of three employees that are creating an instant messaging platform. The background is largely unimportant for the solution, though.
This box takes little to no recon. Checking the SMB share will give you want you need to get started. Reading through or spidering the initial website on port 80 will lead you towards a subdomain on another port, where you will find a nice little web challenge for exploiting inadequate input validation / sanitization and a vulnerable backend PDF-generation library.</description></item><item><title>Intuition</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I hope that Runner got you warmed up for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, Anomalies&amp;hellip; because you&amp;rsquo;re going to need it - this one is tough! Intuition was released as the second box of the season, requiring a wide array of skills to complete. Intuition is very long: by my count, it has ten distinct steps to overcome (which classifies it as being on the harder end of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; difficulty). Interestingly though, Intuition requires very little in terms of &amp;ldquo;exploitation&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about finding and abusing simple misconfigurations/mistakes - which, I think, makes it a more realistic scenario than many HTB boxes.</description></item><item><title>Headless</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/headless/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/headless/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION The penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV Savage Lands, released for week 12, is Headless. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been participating in the season, this is one of the few boxes that I attempted within the 1 week limit. It was totally worth it! This box is an absolute delight, and I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it enough. There aren&amp;rsquo;t any rabbit-holes on this one, and most of the effort will simply be to gain a foothold.</description></item><item><title>CozyHosting</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cozyhosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cozyhosting/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cozyhosting was released as the penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season II &amp;ldquo;Hackers Clash&amp;rdquo;. The box is set up as a server hosting a Spring Boot application, with the challenge revolving around exploiting the web app to gain an initial foothold. The box uses common vulnerabilities and is definitely one of the easier boxes of the season.
Recon for Cozyhosting was important. A little bit of enumeration will yield a token with which you can hijack an existing session, giving you access to an admin dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Sau</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the fourth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Sau is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; Linux box, named after its creator, sau123. At face value, the box is a server hosting a web-app for collecting and displaying HTTP requests. The user is able to define &amp;ldquo;baskets&amp;rdquo; to catch requests, where the requests and their responses can later be analyzed - including their body and headers.</description></item><item><title>Busqueda</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/busqueda/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION For folks like myself that have nada espanol, it turns out &amp;ldquo;busqueda&amp;rdquo; is Spanish for &amp;ldquo;search&amp;rdquo;. It should be no surprise that this box is a search engine. Or rather, it is an aggregator of several search engines all in one.
Warning: This walkthrough contains many spoilers. No spoilers will be unexpected if you read the walkthrough sequentially.
RECON I followed my typical first steps. I set up a directory for the box, with a nmap subdirectory.</description></item></channel></rss>