<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authentication Bypass on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/authentication-bypass/</link><description>Recent content in Authentication Bypass on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:18:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/authentication-bypass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cypher</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cypher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cypher/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Cypher was released for week 8 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 7 Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s marked as Medium difficulty, not because the individual steps were hard, but probably more due the number of steps. In my opinion, this was more of an Easy.
Recon was really easy. A quick &amp;ldquo;spider&amp;rdquo; of the target website and some directory enumeration is all you&amp;rsquo;ll need. This will point you towards both the authentication endpoint and a directory that still has directory listing enabled.</description></item><item><title>MonitorsThree</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitorsthree/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION MonitorsThree was released as the fourth box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s season 6, Heist. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting addition to the &amp;ldquo;Monitors&amp;rdquo; line of boxes, all of which prominently feature the Cacti monitoring tool. This box took a little bit of research to complete, but was generally on the easier side of &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo;.
Recon was almost nonessential. Once you discover the cacti subdomain, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to proceed. Fingerprint the two apps you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered, then check out the main monitorsthree app in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Login Forms</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/login-forms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/login-forms/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION The moment you encounter a login form can be magical: there are so many possibilities at your fingertips&amp;hellip; did they leave some default credentials on the system? Is there an SSRF? Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a way to bypass authentication completely?
Having so many options can be both a blessing and a curse. It can be a little daunting to have to keep so many techniques in mind, and to keep your eyes open for evidence of the form&amp;rsquo;s vulnerability to each.</description></item><item><title>Toolbox</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Continuing on with my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series, Toolbox is the fourth box. For the previous one, see my walkthrough on Buff. Unfortunately, while this box was advertised as Windows, it&amp;rsquo;s actually 100% Linux. Yes, a little disappointing, but it&amp;rsquo;s still good practice. It might not seem like it right away, but if you have some experience with sqlmap, then Toolbox will be a breeze.
Recon was very short; you are only meant to find one thing, and it appears right away.</description></item></channel></rss>