<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSRF on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/ssrf/</link><description>Recent content in SSRF on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/ssrf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lantern</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Is it Linux? I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure&amp;hellip; &amp;#x1f914;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Lantern&lt;/em>, the third box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>, claims to be a Linux box, but in most respects actually it&amp;rsquo;s actually running things as one might in Windows. It isn&amp;rsquo;t until the very end of privesc to root that we find anything Linux-specific. &lt;em>Lantern&lt;/em> is about a generic IT services company running a landing page and an admin panel. What made this one a little special is its extensive use of &lt;em>Blazor&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Server-side Request Forgery (SSRF)</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/ssrf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/ssrf/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="why-write-this">Why write this?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I often forget small steps about testing SSRF. It&amp;rsquo;d be good to have a checklist to remind myself of things to investigate when I find an opportunity for SSRF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is &lt;em>by no means comprehensive&lt;/em>. If you want a longer and more detailed guide, I recommend the &lt;a href="https://book.hacktricks.xyz/pentesting-web/ssrf-server-side-request-forgery">Hacktricks page&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fmiro.medium.com%2Fv2%2Fresize%3Afit%3A1200%2F1*I_x0DdXYVVl__XtvaCgg3Q.png&amp;amp;f=1&amp;amp;nofb=1&amp;amp;ipt=d77ce114bcb7dcd2c1b10a99a4176d4a2a75da3089753efdc16fa4118cbf4097&amp;amp;ipo=images" alt="SSRF">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="address-filter-bypass">ADDRESS FILTER BYPASS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Even if an SSRF vulnerability is present, any half-decent web app will still filter the addresses that can be requested via the SSRFable component. Usually, these constaints are introduced to force the user of the web app to:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Editorial</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em> was released for week 9 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V: &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. With only three steps involved in its solution, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the easiest boxes in the season so far. That being said, twice on this box I ended up kicking myself for having not done something that later seemed obvious, so perhaps &lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em> teaches us a lesson in a more subtle way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is basically no recon involved in &lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em>. Identify the ports, add the domain to your &lt;code>/etc/hosts&lt;/code>, and explore the website. The website only has three pages, so you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly locate the component to attack. From there, you&amp;rsquo;ll find out that this component can be used for SSRF. Follow &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/ssrf/">my SSRF checklist&lt;/a> (Disclaimer: it&amp;rsquo;s a work-in-progress) to expedite things a little. Once you interact with the internally-accessible server via the SSRF, you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly discover some credentials. Use those to gain a foothold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intuition</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I hope that Runner got you warmed up for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>&amp;hellip; because you&amp;rsquo;re going to need it - this one is tough! &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> was released as the second box of the season, requiring a wide array of skills to complete. &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> is very long: by my count, it has ten distinct steps to overcome (which classifies it as being on the harder end of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; difficulty). Interestingly though, &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> requires very little in terms of &amp;ldquo;exploitation&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about finding and abusing simple misconfigurations/mistakes - which, I think, makes it a more realistic scenario than many HTB boxes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Love</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/love/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a week, but now it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back into my “Let’s brush up on Windows!” series. &lt;em>Love&lt;/em> is the fifth box, following &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/toolbox/">&lt;em>Toolbox&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. This box was pretty interesting, definitely worth checking out. I really enjoyed that it avoided the whole &amp;ldquo;Find the CVE and exploit it&amp;rdquo; pattern that many Easy boxes use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It revolves around a &amp;ldquo;File Scanner&amp;rdquo; web app with some terrible security misconfigurations and mistakes. Can you find them all?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bizness</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bizness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bizness/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Bizness&lt;/em>, at first glance, is a cheeky satire of the modern business landing page. It&amp;rsquo;s a website for a fictional company called BizNess that seemingly&amp;hellip; well, I can&amp;rsquo;t really tell what they do. They use a lot of fun buzz words though! &amp;#x1f60e; The entry into the server is all about attacking some well-known ERP software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Foothold on this box is a breeze. A little bit of enumeration and fingerprinting will lead to near-instantaneous success. Privilege escalation to root, however, is much more difficult. It will require you to enumerate very carefully, finding ways to tackle a system bloated with distracting configuration files, plugins, and log files everywhere. Not only that, but when you finally do find what you need, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to apply solid reasoning to take what you&amp;rsquo;ve found and transform it into escalation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keeper</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/keeper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/keeper/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Keeper&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. &lt;em>Keeper&lt;/em> is a very easy box, but with a few tricks up its sleeve. Personally, I found a few aspects of this box to be a little frustrating, but in retrospect those things that I found frustrating were probably the most realistic parts of the box. While it is marked as a Linux box, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a beginner&amp;rsquo;s grasp on some Windows tools to be able to escalate to root.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is &lt;em>Gofer&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. &lt;em>Gofer&lt;/em> is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work. All in all, Gofer is very pleasant to run: the creator of the box clearly put great care into constructing a whole narrative and fictional context for the box. A little bit of enumeration, a few intelligent guesses, and a good knowledge of a few web tricks will gain you foothold&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sau</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/sau/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is still an Active box. It was released as the fourth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. Sau is an &amp;ldquo;Easy&amp;rdquo; Linux box, named after its creator, &lt;strong>sau123&lt;/strong>. At face value, the box is a server hosting a web-app for collecting and displaying HTTP requests. The user is able to define &amp;ldquo;baskets&amp;rdquo; to catch requests, where the requests and their responses can later be analyzed - including their body and headers. Sau is a well-made easy box, with a straightforward path to the end. The foothold has multiple steps, emphasizing the importance of good enumeration and research. Once foothold is gained, recognition and understanding of the underlying vulnerability will ensure a quick sprint to the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>