<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hard on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/hard/</link><description>Recent content in Hard on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/hard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Checker</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/checker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/checker/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Checker was released for week 7 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 7 Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s rated as &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo;, which seems fair and accurate. This box is not straightforward, but has very little guesswork involved, making for a very satisfying puzzle!
Recon is quick and easy. Running some easy web enumeration and clicking through the two websites with a web app proxy is pretty much sufficient. Don&amp;rsquo;t do too much fuzzing, because the box will rate-limit after a hundred or so requests.</description></item><item><title>BigBang</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bigbang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bigbang/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION BigBang was released as the third box of Season 7 Vice. It&amp;rsquo;s rated as Hard, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s more correctly classified as Insane. It took me roughly 35h to complete, research and all.
Recon was pretty simple, at surface level. The target is just a standard Wordpress site. Do a bit of Wordpress-specific recon to find some interesting things about the site. Try finding the interactive elements on the page, and you will quickly see a way to upload files.</description></item><item><title>Lantern</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Is it Linux? I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure&amp;hellip; &amp;#x1f914;
Lantern, the third box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 Heist, claims to be a Linux box, but in most respects actually it&amp;rsquo;s actually running things as one might in Windows. It isn&amp;rsquo;t until the very end of privesc to root that we find anything Linux-specific. Lantern is about a generic IT services company running a landing page and an admin panel. What made this one a little special is its extensive use of Blazor.</description></item><item><title>Resource</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/resource/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/resource/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Resource was released as first box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, Heist. The box was created by the famous user, 0xdf - and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint! This box establishes a whole fictional company and a narrative of the scenario, to a degree that is rare among HTB boxes. We find ourselves attacking an IT service company that is going through a period of their certificate and key management. The box is full of rabbit-holes and distractions, making it slightly frustrating but definitely a more realistic simulation than many other HTB boxes.</description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION In my opinion, Freelancer was a very tough box. It was released as the 7th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V Anomalies. It&amp;rsquo;s about attacking an Active Directory environment that&amp;rsquo;s running a freelancer job market website. Solving this box requires a wide array of skills. However, while a many skills are required, none of the individual steps in the solution are painfully difficult. It is a long box though, with roughly equal amounts of labour required for foothold, the user flag, and for privilege escalation.</description></item><item><title>Intuition</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION I hope that Runner got you warmed up for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, Anomalies&amp;hellip; because you&amp;rsquo;re going to need it - this one is tough! Intuition was released as the second box of the season, requiring a wide array of skills to complete. Intuition is very long: by my count, it has ten distinct steps to overcome (which classifies it as being on the harder end of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; difficulty). Interestingly though, Intuition requires very little in terms of &amp;ldquo;exploitation&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about finding and abusing simple misconfigurations/mistakes - which, I think, makes it a more realistic scenario than many HTB boxes.</description></item><item><title>Cybermonday</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, Cybermondaywas just released! It is the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. The site is a fictional e-commerce site. This box will test your knowledge of SQL, broken authentication, and definitely all the JWT tricks you can imagine! Have fun.
RECON nmap scans For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous boxes in the Open Beta Season II.</description></item><item><title>Download</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Currently, Download is still active. It was released as the eighth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II (Half done the season now!). When Download was released, it was originally marked as Medium - now it is Hard. I agree with this: discovering vulnerabilities on the box was quite obscure, more like a Hard difficulty box, but once you find those vulnerabilities, exploiting them is relatively easy. Gaining a foothold is the hardest part of Download, happening in two steps: the first requires careful code analysis and possibly creating some tools of your own; the second requires a creative re-application of techniques usually used for a different type of application.</description></item><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is Gofer is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II. Gofer is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work.</description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy effects to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals.</description></item></channel></rss>