<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hard on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/hard/</link><description>Recent content in Hard on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/categories/hard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BigBang</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bigbang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2029 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/bigbang/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>BigBang&lt;/em> was released as the third box of Season 7 &lt;em>Vice&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s rated as Hard, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s more correctly classified as Insane. It took me roughly 35h to complete, research and all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recon was pretty simple, at surface level. The target is just a standard Wordpress site. Do a bit of Wordpress-specific recon to find some interesting things about the site. Try finding the interactive elements on the page, and you will quickly see a way to upload files. If you can turn this into an arbitrary upload, you&amp;rsquo;re well on the way to foothold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lantern</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/lantern/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Is it Linux? I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure&amp;hellip; &amp;#x1f914;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Lantern&lt;/em>, the third box in HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6 &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>, claims to be a Linux box, but in most respects actually it&amp;rsquo;s actually running things as one might in Windows. It isn&amp;rsquo;t until the very end of privesc to root that we find anything Linux-specific. &lt;em>Lantern&lt;/em> is about a generic IT services company running a landing page and an admin panel. What made this one a little special is its extensive use of &lt;em>Blazor&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resource</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/resource/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/resource/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Resource&lt;/em> was released as first box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 6, &lt;em>Heist&lt;/em>. The box was created by the famous user, &lt;code>0xdf&lt;/code> - and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint! This box establishes a whole fictional company and a narrative of the scenario, to a degree that is rare among HTB boxes. We find ourselves attacking an IT service company that is going through a period of their certificate and key management. The box is full of rabbit-holes and distractions, making it slightly frustrating but definitely a more realistic simulation than many other HTB boxes. Although the steps in &lt;em>Resource&lt;/em> tend to be short, they are numerous: by my count, I had to do five pivots between separate users to complete this box.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/freelancer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my opinion, &lt;em>Freelancer&lt;/em> was a very tough box. It was released as the 7th box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s about attacking an Active Directory environment that&amp;rsquo;s running a freelancer job market website. Solving this box requires a wide array of skills. However, while a many skills are required, none of the individual steps in the solution are painfully difficult. It is a long box though, with roughly equal amounts of labour required for foothold, the user flag, and for privilege escalation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intuition</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intuition/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I hope that Runner got you warmed up for HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season 5, &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>&amp;hellip; because you&amp;rsquo;re going to need it - this one is tough! &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> was released as the second box of the season, requiring a wide array of skills to complete. &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> is very long: by my count, it has ten distinct steps to overcome (which classifies it as being on the harder end of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; difficulty). Interestingly though, &lt;em>Intuition&lt;/em> requires very little in terms of &amp;ldquo;exploitation&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s mostly about finding and abusing simple misconfigurations/mistakes - which, I think, makes it a more realistic scenario than many HTB boxes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cybermonday</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, &lt;em>Cybermonday&lt;/em>was just released! It is the ninth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. The site is a fictional e-commerce site. This box will test your knowledge of SQL, broken authentication, and definitely all the JWT tricks you can imagine! Have fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/cybermonday/index%20page.png" alt="title picture">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recon">RECON&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="nmap-scans">nmap scans&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For this box, I&amp;rsquo;m running the same enumeration strategy as the previous boxes in the &lt;em>Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. I set up a directory for the box, with a &lt;code>nmap&lt;/code> subdirectory. Then set &lt;code>$RADDR&lt;/code> to my target machine&amp;rsquo;s IP, and scanned it with a simple but broad port scan:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Download</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Download&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the eighth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em> (Half done the season now!). When &lt;em>Download&lt;/em> was released, it was originally marked as Medium - now it is Hard. I agree with this: discovering vulnerabilities on the box was quite obscure, more like a Hard difficulty box, but once you find those vulnerabilities, exploiting them is relatively easy. Gaining a foothold is the hardest part of &lt;em>Download&lt;/em>, happening in two steps: the first requires careful code analysis and possibly creating some tools of your own; the second requires a creative re-application of techniques usually used for a different type of application. For privilege escalation A bit of knowledge of &lt;em>the old ways&lt;/em> of privilege escalation will be invaluable for getting the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gofer</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/gofer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of writing this walkthrough, this is &lt;em>Gofer&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the seventh box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. &lt;em>Gofer&lt;/em> is labeled as a &amp;ldquo;Hard&amp;rdquo; Linux box, but in reality it was probably closer to medium difficulty. This box centers around a fictional company that provides web development and web design services, although, given the security breach you&amp;rsquo;re about to dive into, perhaps they should transition to a different line of work. All in all, Gofer is very pleasant to run: the creator of the box clearly put great care into constructing a whole narrative and fictional context for the box. A little bit of enumeration, a few intelligent guesses, and a good knowledge of a few web tricks will gain you foothold&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intentions</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/intentions/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Intentions was released on July 1, 2023 as the third box in &lt;em>Hackers Clash Open Beta Season II&lt;/em>. It is a website that functions as an online image gallery. Users are also able to apply fancy &lt;em>effects&lt;/em> to images within the gallery. This box comes with cute animals, food pics, and a painfully difficult foothold. Achieving the user flag after foothold is relatively straightforward but reinforces some good hacking fundamentals. The root flag is quick, but requires wrapping your head around some cryptography concepts and formulating a customized solution to overcome the problem.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>