<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SUID Bash on 4wayhandshake</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/suid-bash/</link><description>Recent content in SUID Bash on 4wayhandshake</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/tags/suid-bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Editorial</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/editorial/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em> was released for week 9 of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season V: &lt;em>Anomalies&lt;/em>. With only three steps involved in its solution, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the easiest boxes in the season so far. That being said, twice on this box I ended up kicking myself for having not done something that later seemed obvious, so perhaps &lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em> teaches us a lesson in a more subtle way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is basically no recon involved in &lt;em>Editorial&lt;/em>. Identify the ports, add the domain to your &lt;code>/etc/hosts&lt;/code>, and explore the website. The website only has three pages, so you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly locate the component to attack. From there, you&amp;rsquo;ll find out that this component can be used for SSRF. Follow &lt;a href="https://4wayhandshake.github.io/strategy/ssrf/">my SSRF checklist&lt;/a> (Disclaimer: it&amp;rsquo;s a work-in-progress) to expedite things a little. Once you interact with the internally-accessible server via the SSRF, you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly discover some credentials. Use those to gain a foothold.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Headless</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/headless/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/headless/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The penultimate box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV &lt;em>Savage Lands&lt;/em>, released for week 12, is &lt;em>Headless&lt;/em>. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been participating in the season, this is one of the few boxes that I attempted within the 1 week limit. It was totally worth it! This box is an absolute delight, and I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it enough. There aren&amp;rsquo;t any rabbit-holes on this one, and most of the effort will simply be to gain a foothold. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick box that reinforces some good hacking fundamentals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitored</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/monitored/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Monitored&lt;/em> was released as the second box of HTB&amp;rsquo;s Season IV, &amp;ldquo;Savage Lands&amp;rdquo;. As is evident from visiting the index page of the box, this one centers around Nagios, an IT administration and monitoring solution for enterprise. The documentation for Nagios XI is extremely scant, which proves to be one of the main stumbling points of this box. At least 90% of the effort for this box is spent on gaining a foothold - a moment which feels perpetually just out-of-reach. Nevertheless, this box is a hard teacher: reminding us to never give up and always &lt;em>hack harder&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Download</title><link>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://4wayhandshake.github.io/walkthrough/download/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently, &lt;em>Download&lt;/em> is still active. It was released as the eighth box for HTB&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Hackers Clash: Open Beta Season II&lt;/em> (Half done the season now!). When &lt;em>Download&lt;/em> was released, it was originally marked as Medium - now it is Hard. I agree with this: discovering vulnerabilities on the box was quite obscure, more like a Hard difficulty box, but once you find those vulnerabilities, exploiting them is relatively easy. Gaining a foothold is the hardest part of &lt;em>Download&lt;/em>, happening in two steps: the first requires careful code analysis and possibly creating some tools of your own; the second requires a creative re-application of techniques usually used for a different type of application. For privilege escalation A bit of knowledge of &lt;em>the old ways&lt;/em> of privilege escalation will be invaluable for getting the root flag.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>